<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Real User Monitoring Exercise on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.14/en/s4r/6-rum/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Real User Monitoring Exercise on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.14/en/s4r/6-rum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1. RUM Dashboard</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.14/en/s4r/6-rum/1-rum-dashboard/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.14/en/s4r/6-rum/1-rum-dashboard/index.html</guid><description>In Splunk Observability Cloud from the main menu, click on RUM. From the drop-downs ensure the following is set/selected:
Timeframe is set to -15m. Environment selected is [NAME OF WORKSHOP]-workshop. App selected is [NAME OF WORKSHOP]-shop. Source is set to All. This view has already been covered in the short introduction earlier. Next, click on the [NAME OF WORKSHOP]-workshop above the Page Views / JavaScript Errors chart.
This will bring up a dashboard view breaking down the metrics by UX Metrics, Front-end Health, Back-end Health and Custom Events.</description></item><item><title>2. Tag Spotlight</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.14/en/s4r/6-rum/2-tag-spotlight/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.14/en/s4r/6-rum/2-tag-spotlight/index.html</guid><description>Click the Custom Events tab and have a look at the Custom Event Latency chart. The metrics shown here show the application latency. The comparison metrics to the side show the latency compared to 1 hour ago (which is selected in the top filter bar). Click on the see all link under the chart title.
In this dashboard view, you are presented with all the tags associated with the RUM data.</description></item><item><title>3. Session Replay</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.14/en/s4r/6-rum/3-session-replay/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.14/en/s4r/6-rum/3-session-replay/index.html</guid><description>In the User Sessions table the sessions, click on the top Session ID (it should be around 50 seconds, or longer). This will bring on the RUM Session view.
A session is a collection of traces that correspond to the actions a single user takes when interacting with an application over a period of time. By default, a session lasts until 15 minutes have passed from the last event captured in the session.</description></item><item><title>4. User Sessions</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.14/en/s4r/6-rum/4-user-sessions/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.14/en/s4r/6-rum/4-user-sessions/index.html</guid><description>Click on the workflow ensuring it says frontend:/cart/checkout Move on to APM Close the RUM Session Replay by clicking on the X in the top right corner. Here, we can see the custom event PlaceOrder. Notice the length of the span. This is the time it took to complete the order, not good!
Next, scroll down the page and you will see the Tags metadata (which is used in Tag Spotlight).</description></item></channel></rss>