<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Splunk4Rookies - Observability on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.10/en/s4r/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Splunk4Rookies - Observability on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.10/en/s4r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Workshop Agenda</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.10/en/s4r/01-workshop-goals/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.10/en/s4r/01-workshop-goals/index.html</guid><description>The goal of this workshop is to make you famliar with the Splunk Observability Suite and its key features. For this we have provided you with a complete application that includes a Website and a number of back end services that make up the complete application.
During this workshop you will expierince issues with this application. The goal of this excercise is to use several of the key features from the Splunk observability suite to detect the issue, locate the cause of the issue, allowing your developmemt teams to very quickly resolve the issue.</description></item><item><title>Quick guide to the Splunk Observability Suite UI</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.10/en/s4r/02-inital-ui-tour/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.10/en/s4r/02-inital-ui-tour/index.html</guid><description>A quick tour of the ui</description></item><item><title>Shopping at the Online Boutique</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.10/en/s4r/03-online-boutique/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.10/en/s4r/03-online-boutique/index.html</guid><description>For attendees that are taking the pre-configured workshop, the application will already be deployed for you and your instructor will provide with a link to the Online Boutique application.
For attendees taking the interactive workshop, you will need to install OpenTelemetry and deploy the application. Hit the **Ninja button below to expand the instructions.
Ninja: Interactive workshop build steps Install the OpenTelemetry Collector using the Splunk Helm chart. First, add the Splunk Helm chart repository to Helm and update.</description></item><item><title>Splunk RUM</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.10/en/s4r/04-rum/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.10/en/s4r/04-rum/index.html</guid><description>Splunk Real User Monitoring (RUM) allows your teams to quickly identify and eliminate customer-facing issues across your entire architecture.
Splunk RUM collects performance metrics, web vitals, errors, and other forms of data for every user session to enable you to detect and troubleshoot problems in your application.
In Splunk Observability Cloud click on the RUM tab in the left navigation bar.
As we know, modern web experiences can appear simple, but are complex, asynchronous systems.</description></item><item><title>Splunk APM</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.10/en/s4r/05-apm/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.10/en/s4r/05-apm/index.html</guid><description>Hover over the APM link
This is where the end to end value of the Splunk Observability Cloud starts to show. We can hover over this APM link to reveal some quick, at a glance, info about what’s happening on the backend.
This performance summary is clearly showing two actionable things:
Time is being spent in the app (not db, network, or external); and There are errors occurring in these back-end services, and I can see precisely which service is producing the “root cause” for this particular trace (in this case the payment service in dark red).</description></item><item><title>Splunk Log Observer</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.10/en/s4r/06-log-observer/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.10/en/s4r/06-log-observer/index.html</guid><description>Hover over the boxes at the bottom of the trace
We are federating logs across multiple Splunk instances and indexes, which can be extremely useful when I have logs in multiple places – on-prem or in the cloud.
Let’s navigate to the linked logs.
Click on the logs that are in Splunk Cloud integration
I can now see the log entries coming from this specific trace.
Search for “severity” on the right under the “Fields” section, hover over “error”, and click the = next to “error”</description></item><item><title>Splunk Synthetics</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.10/en/s4r/07-synthetics/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.10/en/s4r/07-synthetics/index.html</guid><description>Use the Splunk Observability Suite to check the perfomance of your Website/API Endpoint So far we have have tested the perfomance of our Website by visting and running manual testscenario&amp;rsquo;s to see how our web site perfomed. however this is not something you can 24 hours a day &amp;amp; 7 days a week.
if you would be testing your website perfomance and behaviourmanually in production the likely source telling you that your site is slow or not performant is Social Media or Down Detector web sites these days.</description></item><item><title>Workshop Wrap-up</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.10/en/s4r/08-wrap-up/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.10/en/s4r/08-wrap-up/index.html</guid><description>This wraps up the Splunk for Rookies Workshop of the Splunk Observability Cloud. We were able to:
Understand what real users were experiencing Saw how we can detect these issue though Detectors, Dasboardsand Synthetic Tests Troubleshoot a particularly long page load, by following it’s trace across the front and back end and right to the log entries Use tag spotlight, in both RUM and APM, to understand blast radius and context for our performance issues and errors Today we didn’t even talk about the power of the rest of Splunk Observability Cloud, such as:</description></item></channel></rss>