<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Splunk4Rookies - Observability Cloud on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/s4r/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Splunk4Rookies - Observability Cloud on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/s4r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Workshop Overview</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/s4r/1-workshop-goals/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/s4r/1-workshop-goals/index.html</guid><description>Introduction The goal of this workshop is to experience an issue and use Splunk Observability Cloud to troubleshoot and identify the root cause. For this, we have provided a complete microservices-based application running in Kubernetes that has been instrumented to send metrics, traces, and logs to Splunk Observability Cloud.
Who should attend? Those wanting to gain an understanding of Splunk Observability in a hands-on environment. This workshop is designed for people with little or no experience with Splunk Observability.</description></item><item><title>What is OpenTelemetry &amp; why should you care?</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/s4r/2-opentelemetry/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/s4r/2-opentelemetry/index.html</guid><description>OpenTelemetry With the rise of cloud computing, microservices architectures, and ever-more complex business requirements, the need for Observability has never been greater. Observability is the ability to understand the internal state of a system by examining its outputs. In the context of software, this means being able to understand the internal state of a system by examining its telemetry data, which includes metrics, traces, and logs.
To make a system observable, it must be instrumented.</description></item><item><title>UI - Quick Tour 🚌</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/index.html</guid><description>We are going to start with a short walkthrough of the various components of Splunk Observability Cloud. The aim of this is to get you familiar with the UI.
Signing in to Splunk Observability Cloud Real User Monitoring (RUM) Application Performance Monitoring (APM) Log Observer Synthetics Infrastructure Monitoring Tip The easiest way to navigate through this workshop is by using:
the left/right arrows (&amp;lt; | &amp;gt;) on the top right of this page the left (◀️) and right (▶️) cursor keys on your keyboard</description></item><item><title>Let's go shopping 💶</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/s4r/4-online-boutique/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/s4r/4-online-boutique/index.html</guid><description>Persona You are a hip urban professional, longing to buy your next novelty items in the famous Online Boutique shop. You have heard that the Online Boutique is the place to go for all your hipster needs.
The purpose of this exercise is for you to interact with the Online Boutique web application. This is a sample application that is used to demonstrate the capabilities of Splunk Observability Cloud. The application is a simple e-commerce site that allows you to browse items, add them to your cart, and then checkout.</description></item><item><title>Splunk RUM</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/s4r/5-rum/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/s4r/5-rum/index.html</guid><description>Persona You are a frontend engineer, or an SRE tasked to do the first triage of a performance issue. You have been asked to investigate a potential customer satisfaction issue with the Online Boutique application.
We are going to examine the real user data that has been provided by the telemetry received from all participants&amp;rsquo; browser sessions. The goal is to find a browser, mobile or tablet session that performed poorly and begin the troubleshooting process.</description></item><item><title>Splunk APM</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/s4r/6-apm/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/s4r/6-apm/index.html</guid><description>Persona You are a back-end developer and you have been called in to help investigate an issue found by the SRE. The SRE has identified a poor user experience and has asked you to investigate the issue.
Discover the power of full end-to-end visibility by jumping from a RUM trace (front-end) to an APM trace (back-end). All the services are sending telemetry (traces and spans) that Splunk Observability Cloud can visualize, analyze and use to detect anomalies and errors.</description></item><item><title>Splunk Log Observer</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/s4r/7-log-observer/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/s4r/7-log-observer/index.html</guid><description>Persona Remaining in your back-end developer role, you need to inspect the logs from your application to determine the root cause of the issue.
Using the content related to the APM trace (logs) we will now use Splunk Log Observer to drill down further to understand exactly what the problem is.
Related Content is a powerful feature that allows you to jump from one component to another and is available for metrics, traces and logs.</description></item><item><title>Splunk Synthetics</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/s4r/8-synthetics/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/s4r/8-synthetics/index.html</guid><description>Persona Putting your SRE hat back on, you have been asked to set up monitoring for the Online Boutique. You need to ensure that the application is available and performing well 24 hours a day, 7 days a week.
Wouldn’t it be great if we could have 24/7 monitoring of our application, and be alerted when there is a problem? This is where Synthetics comes in. We will show you a simple test that runs every 1 minute and checks the performance and availability of a typical user journey through the Online Boutique.</description></item><item><title>Custom Service Health Dashboard 🏥</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/index.html</guid><description>Persona As the SRE hat suits you let&amp;rsquo;s keep it on as you have been asked to build a custom Service Health Dashboard for the paymentservice. The requirement is to display RED metrics, logs and Synthetic test duration results.
It is common for development and SRE teams to require a summary of the health of their applications and/or services. More often or not these are displayed on wall-mounted TVs. Splunk Observability Cloud has the perfect solution for this by creating custom dashboards.</description></item><item><title>Workshop Wrap-up 🎁</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/s4r/10-wrap-up/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/s4r/10-wrap-up/index.html</guid><description>Congratulations, you have completed the Splunk4Rookies - Observability Cloud Workshop. Today, you have become familiar with how to use Splunk Observability Cloud to monitor your applications and infrastructure.
Celebrate your achievement by adding this certificate to your LinkedIn profile.
Let&amp;rsquo;s recap what we have learned and what you can do next.</description></item></channel></rss>