<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Custom Service Health Dashboard on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.16/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Custom Service Health Dashboard on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.16/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dashboard Introduction</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.16/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/1-custom-dashboard/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.16/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/1-custom-dashboard/index.html</guid><description>As we already saved some useful log charts in a dashboard in the Log Observer exercise, we are going to extend that dashboard.
Exercise Go back to your dashboard with the two log charts, by clicking on *Dashboards, and select your dashboard group from the list of linked dashboards at the bottom of the page. This should bring you back to your previously saved dashboard. Even if the log information is useful, it will need more information to have it make sense for our team so let&amp;rsquo;s add a bit more information The first step is adding a description chart to the dashboard.</description></item><item><title>Adding charts to the Service Health Dashboard</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.16/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/2-add-chart/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.16/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/2-add-chart/index.html</guid><description>In this section, we are going to use the Copy and Paste functionality to extend our dashboard. The next step will be to add some more charts for our payment service.
Exercise Find your Service Health Dashboard. Select the 2+ at the top of the page and select Paste charts, this will create the charts in your custom dashboard. Add sf_environment=[WORKSHOPNAME] and sf_service=payment_service to the override filter box. Click Save .</description></item><item><title>Create Custom Chart &amp; add to Dashboard</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.16/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/3-custom-chart/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.16/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/3-custom-chart/index.html</guid><description>As we already saved some useful log charts in a dashboard in the Log Observer exercise, we are going to extend that dashboard.
Exercise Go back to your dashboard with the two log charts, by clicking on Dashboards, and select your dashboard group from the list of linked dashboards at the bottom of the page. This should bring you back to your previously saved dashboard. Even if the log information is useful, it will need more information to have it make sense for our team so let&amp;rsquo;s add a bit more information The first step is adding a description chart to the dashboard.</description></item></channel></rss>