<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Infrastructure Overview on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.24/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/6-infrastructure-home/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Infrastructure Overview on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.24/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/6-infrastructure-home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Infrastructure Overview</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.24/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/6-infrastructure-home/1-infrastructure-overview/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.24/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/6-infrastructure-home/1-infrastructure-overview/index.html</guid><description>Splunk Infrastructure Monitoring (IM) is a market-leading monitoring and observability service for hybrid cloud environments. Built on a patented streaming architecture, it provides a real-time solution for engineering teams to visualize and analyze performance across infrastructure, services, and applications in a fraction of the time and with greater accuracy than traditional solutions.
OpenTelemetry standardization: Gives you full control over your data — freeing you from vendor lock-in and implementing proprietary agents.</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure Navigators</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.24/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/6-infrastructure-home/2-infrastructure-home/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.24/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/6-infrastructure-home/2-infrastructure-home/index.html</guid><description>Click on Infrastructure in the main menu, the Infrastructure Home Page is made up of 4 distinct sections.
Onboarding Pane: Training videos and links to documentation to get you started with Splunk Infrastructure Monitoring. Time &amp;amp; Filter Pane: Time window (not configurable at the top level) Integrations Pane: List of all the technologies that are sending metrics to Splunk Observability Cloud. Tile Pane: Total number of services being monitored broken down by integration.</description></item></channel></rss>