<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Connecting to the Splunk observability UI on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/2-initial-tour/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Connecting to the Splunk observability UI on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/2-initial-tour/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1. Home/Landing Page</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/2-initial-tour/1-homepage/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/2-initial-tour/1-homepage/index.html</guid><description>5 minutes After you registered and logged into the Splunk Observability UI, as described here, you will be taken to the Observability Suite Home Page. This Home or Landing page has 6 distinct section that provide either useful information or allows you to navigate the Splunk Observability Suite.
Explore Data Pane, Here you can see what function of the Suite are active and you can add additional integrations. Onboarding Pane, Here you will find video&amp;rsquo;s and references to document pages of interest.</description></item><item><title>2. APM Home Page</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/2-initial-tour/2-apm-home/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/2-initial-tour/2-apm-home/index.html</guid><description>5 minutes If you have not done so already, please select from the Main menu. This will bring you to the APM Home page.
WIP WIP WIP WIP WIP WIP
this Page has 6 distinct sections that provide either useful information or allows you to navigate the Splunk Observability Suite.
Explore Data Pane, Here you can see what function of the Suite are active and you can add additional integrations.</description></item><item><title>6. Synthetics Home Page</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/2-initial-tour/6-synthetics-home/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/2-initial-tour/6-synthetics-home/index.html</guid><description>5 minutes If you have not done so yet, select Splunk Synthetic from the menu bar on the right by selecting the (the robot icon) . This will bring us to the Synthetic Home Page. It has 3 distinct sections that provide either useful information or allows you pick or create a Synthetic Test.
Onboarding Pane, Here you will find video&amp;rsquo;s and information related to Splunk Synthetics. (Can be closed by pressing the X, if space is a premium) Test Pane, Here you find the list of all the test that are active in your org, and you can select them to see the results Create Test Pane, This drop down pane gives you the option to create a new Synthetic test.</description></item><item><title>7. Infrastructure Home Page</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/2-initial-tour/7-infrastructure-home/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/2-initial-tour/7-infrastructure-home/index.html</guid><description>5 minutes This section is split in multiple sections and is going to be a little longer, the first section is a quick intro to the main page, followed by a few sections to dive deeper into some of the special features of the Splunk Observability suite, before we start to use our application and validate performance.
Please select Splunk Infrastructure from the menu bar on the right by selecting the .</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure Exercise 1</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/2-initial-tour/im-exercise/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/2-initial-tour/im-exercise/index.html</guid><description>7 minutes This is the third section of our Kubernetes Navigator exercise.
Please select the K8s nodes tile from the Tile pane if you have not yet done so. (Select Kubernetes as your Technology). This will bring you to the Kubernetes Navigator Page.
The screenshot above shows the main part of the kubernetes navigator. It will show all the clusters &amp;amp; their nodes that send metrics to the Splunk Observability Suite.</description></item><item><title>Log on FAQ</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/2-initial-tour/99-login-faq/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/2-initial-tour/99-login-faq/index.html</guid><description>This FAQ will address some of the more common issues we have encounter with when login into the Workshop and their solutions the goal og this section is to make you comfortable with the UI of the splunkObservability suite. First we wil examine the main components in the ui, followed by an exercise to get you started.
1. Invite email or password renewal email not arriving The first step to take is to search for an email from noreply@signalfx.</description></item></channel></rss>