<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RUM on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/2-rum/index.html</link><description>Recent content in RUM on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/2-rum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/2-rum/1-overview/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/2-rum/1-overview/index.html</guid><description>The aim of this Splunk Real User Monitoring (RUM) workshop is to let you:
Shop for items on the Online Boutique to create traffic, and create RUM User Sessions1 that you can view in the Splunk Observability Suite. See an overview of the performance of all your application(s) in the Application Summary Dashboard Examine the performance of a specific website with RUM metrics. In order to reach this goal, we will use an online boutique to order various products.</description></item><item><title>RUM instrumentation in a browser app</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/2-rum/2-setup/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/2-rum/2-setup/index.html</guid><description>Check the HEAD section of the Online-boutique webpage in your browser Find the code that instruments RUM 1. Browse to the Online Boutique Your workshop instructor will provide you with the Online Boutique URL that has RUM installed so that you can complete the next steps.
2. Inspecting the HTML source The changes needed for RUM are placed in the &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; section of the hosts Web page. Right click to view the page source or to inspect the code.</description></item><item><title>RUM Landing Page</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/2-rum/3-rum-landing/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/2-rum/3-rum-landing/index.html</guid><description>Visit the RUM landing page and and check the overview of the performance of all your RUM enabled applications with the Application Summary Dashboard (Both Mobile and Web based) 1. Visit the RUM Landing Page Login into Splunk Observability. From the left side menu bar select RUM . This will bring you to your the RUM Landing Page.
The goal of this page is to give you in a single page, a clear indication of the health, performance and potential errors found in your application(s) and allow you to dive deeper into the information about your User Sessions collected from your web page/App.</description></item><item><title>Check Browser Applications health at a glance</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/2-rum/4-browser-summary/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/2-rum/4-browser-summary/index.html</guid><description>Get familiar with the UI and options available from this landing page Identify Page Views/JavaScript Errors and Request/Errors in a single view Check the Web Vitals metrics and any Detector that has fired for in relation to your Browser Application Application Summary Dashboard 1.Header Bar As seen in the previous section the RUM Application Summary Dashboard consists of 5 major sections. The first section is the selection header, where you can collapse the Pane via the Browser icon or the &amp;gt; in front of the application name, which is jmcj-store in the example below.</description></item><item><title>Analyzing RUM Metrics</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/2-rum/5-analyzing-metrics/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/2-rum/5-analyzing-metrics/index.html</guid><description>See RUM Metrics and Session information in the RUM UI See correlated APM traces in the RUM &amp;amp; APM UI 1. RUM Overview Pages From your RUM Application Summary Dashboard you can see detailed information by opening the Application Overview Page via the tripple dot menu on the right by selecting Open Application Overview or by clicking the link with your application name which is jmcj-rum-app in the example below.</description></item><item><title>Analyzing RUM Tags in the Tag Spotlight view</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/2-rum/6-tag-spotlight/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/2-rum/6-tag-spotlight/index.html</guid><description>Look into the Metrics views for the various endpoints and use the Tags sent via the Tag spotlight for deeper analysis 1. Find an url for the Cart endpoint From the RUM Overview page, please select the url for the Cart endpoint to dive deeper into the information available for this endpoint.
Once you have selected and clicked on the blue url, you will find yourself in the Tag Spotlight overview</description></item><item><title>Analyzing RUM Sessions</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/2-rum/7-rum-sessions/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/2-rum/7-rum-sessions/index.html</guid><description>Dive into RUM Session information in the RUM UI Identify Javascript errors in the Span of an user interaction 1. Again select the cart URL After you have focussed the time slot with the time selector, you need to reselect the cart url from Url Name view, as shown below:
In the example above we selected http://34.246.124.162:81/cart
2. Drill down in the Sessions After you have analyzed the information and drilled down via the Tag Spotlight to a subset of the traces, you can view the actual session as it was run by the end-user&amp;rsquo;s browser.</description></item></channel></rss>