<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Incident Lifecycle on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/other/10-oncall/incident_lifecycle/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Incident Lifecycle on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/other/10-oncall/incident_lifecycle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create Incidents</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/other/10-oncall/incident_lifecycle/create_incidents/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/other/10-oncall/incident_lifecycle/create_incidents/index.html</guid><description>Aim The aim of this module is for you to place yourself &amp;lsquo;On-Call&amp;rsquo; then generate an Incident using the supplied EC2 Instance so you can then work through the lifecycle of an Incident.
1. On-Call Before generating any incidents you should assign yourself to the current Shift within your Follow the Sun Support - Business Hours Rotation and also place yourself On-Call.
Click on the Schedule link within your Team in the People section on the left, or navigate to Teams → [Your Team] → Rotations Expand the Follow the Sun Support - Business Hours Rotation Click on the Manage members icon (the figures) for the current active shift depending on your time zone Use the Select a user to add&amp;hellip; dropdown to add yourself to the shift Then click on Set Current next to your name to make yourself the current on-call user within the shift You should now get a Push Notification to your phone informing you that You Are Now On-Call 2.</description></item><item><title>Manage Incidents</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/other/10-oncall/incident_lifecycle/manage_incidents/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/other/10-oncall/incident_lifecycle/manage_incidents/index.html</guid><description>1. Acknowledge Use your Splunk On-Call App on your phone to acknowledge the Incident by clicking on the push notification &amp;hellip;
&amp;hellip;to open the alert in the Splunk On-Call mobile app, then clicking on either the single tick in the top right hand corner, or the Acknowledge link to acknowledge the incident and stop the escalation process.
The :fontawesome-solid-check: will then transform into a :fontawesome-solid-check::fontawesome-solid-check:, and the status will change from TRIGGERED to ACKNOWLEDGED.</description></item></channel></rss>