<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Splunk Observability Workshops on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.35/en/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Splunk Observability Workshops on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.35/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Splunk4Rookies - Observability</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.35/en/s4r/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.35/en/s4r/index.html</guid><description>2 minutes AuthorsRobert Castley &amp;amp; Pieter Hagen
In this workshop, we will be showing how Splunk Observability Cloud provides instant visibility of the user experience – from the perspective of the front-end application to its back-end services – Letting you experience some of the most compelling product features and differentiators of Splunk Observability Cloud:
Infrastructure Monitoring Full-fidelity Real User Monitoring (RUM) Complete end-to-end NoSample™ Full-fidelity trace visibility with Application Performance Monitoring (APM) No code log querying Synthetic Monitoring Finding root causes with tag analytics and error stacks Related content A key factor in building the Splunk Observability Cloud is to unify telemetry data to create a complete picture of an end-user experience and your application stack.</description></item><item><title>Splunk IM</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.35/en/imt/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.35/en/imt/index.html</guid><description>During this technical Splunk Observability Cloud Infrastructure Monitoring and APM Workshop, you will build out an environment based on a lightweight Kubernetes1 cluster.
To simplify the workshop modules, a pre-configured AWS/EC2 instance is provided.
The instance is pre-configured with all the software required to deploy the Splunk OpenTelemetry Connector2 in Kubernetes, deploy an NGINX^3 ReplicaSet^4 and finally deploy a microservices-based application which has been instrumented using OpenTelemetry to send metrics, traces, spans and logs3.</description></item><item><title>Splunk APM</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.35/en/apm/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.35/en/apm/index.html</guid><description>Splunk APM is a NoSample™ Full-fidelity application performance monitoring and troubleshooting solution for cloud-native, microservices-based applications.
By collecting all traces, instead of a sampled subset, no anomaly goes undetected. Whether a user experiences an error or longer-than-usual latency, you’ll be able to know and act on it within seconds. Furthermore, not all bad behavior results in errors — as your developers create new applications they need to know whether their canary releases provide the expected results.</description></item><item><title>Ninja Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.35/en/other/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.35/en/other/index.html</guid><description>PetClinic Java WorkshopA workshop using Zero Configuration Auto-Instrumentation for Java.
Getting Data In (GDI) with OTel and UFLearn how to get data into Splunk Observability Cloud with OpenTelemetry and the Splunk Universal Forwarder.
Monitoring Horizontal Pod Autoscaling in KubernetesThis workshop will equip you with the basic understanding of monitoring Kubernetes using the Splunk OpenTelemetry Collector
Build a Distributed Trace in Lambda and KinesisThis workshop will equip you with how a distributed trace is constructed for a small serverless application that runs on AWS Lambda, producing and consuming a message via AWS Kinesis</description></item><item><title>Resources</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.35/en/resources/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.35/en/resources/index.html</guid><description>Frequently Asked QuestionsA collection of the common questions and their answers associated with Observability, DevOps, Incident Response and Splunk On-Call.
Dimension, Properties and TagsOne conversation that frequently comes up is Dimensions vs Properties and when you should use one verus the other.
Naming Conventions for Tagging with OpenTelemetry and SplunkWhen deploying OpenTelemetry in a large organization, it’s critical to define a standardized naming convention for tagging, and a governance process to ensure the convention is adhered to.</description></item><item><title>Workshop Setup</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.35/en/workshop-setup/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.35/en/workshop-setup/index.html</guid><description>Welcome to the Observability Workshop Setup Guide. This guide will walk you through the steps required to set up your workshop environments.
Existing Workshop Orgs The following Organizations can be used for running Observability Workshops. They have all the features enabled to successfully run any of the available workshops:
CoE Workshop EMEA (EU0) Observability Workshop EMEA (EU0) Observability Workshop AMER (US1) APAC-O11y-Workshop (US1) Trial Orgs It is also possible to create workshop environments in any trial Org.</description></item></channel></rss>