<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>UI - Quick Tour 🚌 :: Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.70/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/index.html</link><description>A quick tour of the Splunk Observability Cloud UI.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.70/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Started</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.70/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/1-homepage/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.70/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/1-homepage/index.html</guid><description>Learn how to get started with Splunk Observability Cloud.</description></item><item><title>Real User Monitoring Overview</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.70/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/2-rum-home/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.70/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/2-rum-home/index.html</guid><description>Learn about Splunk RUM and how it can help you monitor the full user experience of every web and mobile session.</description></item><item><title>Application Performance Monitoring Overview</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.70/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/3-apm-home/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.70/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/3-apm-home/index.html</guid><description>Splunk APM provides a NoSample™ end-to-end visibility of every service and its dependency to solve problems quicker across monoliths and microservices. Teams can immediately detect problems from new deployments, confidently troubleshoot by scoping and isolating the source of an issue, and optimize service performance by understanding how back-end services impact end users and business workflows.
Real-time monitoring and alerting: Splunk provides out-of-the-box service dashboards and automatically detects and alerts on RED metrics (rate, error and duration) when there is a sudden change. Dynamic telemetry maps: Easily visualize service performance in modern production environments in real-time. End-to-end visibility of service performance from infrastructure, applications, end users, and all dependencies helps quickly scope new issues and troubleshoot more effectively.
Intelligent tagging and analysis: View all tags from your business, infrastructure and applications in one place to easily compare new trends in latency or errors to their specific tag values.
AI-directed troubleshooting identifies the most impactful issues: Instead of manually digging through individual dashboards, isolate problems more efficiently. Automatically identify anomalies and the sources of errors that impact services and customers the most.
Complete distributed tracing analyses every transaction: Identify problems in your cloud-native environment more effectively. Splunk distributed tracing visualizes and correlates every transaction from the back-end and front-end in context with your infrastructure, business workflows and applications.
Full stack correlation: Within Splunk Observability, APM links traces, metrics, logs and profiling together to easily understand the performance of every component and its dependency across your stack.
Monitor database query performance: Easily identify how slow and high execution queries from SQL and NoSQL databases impact your services, endpoints and business workflows — no instrumentation required.</description></item><item><title>Log Observer Overview</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.70/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/4-log-observer-home/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.70/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/4-log-observer-home/index.html</guid><description>Log Observer Connect allows you to seamlessly bring in the same log data from your Splunk Platform into an intuitive and no-code interface designed to help you find and fix problems quickly. You can easily perform log-based analysis and seamlessly correlate your logs with Splunk Infrastructure Monitoring’s real-time metrics and Splunk APM traces in one place.
End-to-end visibility: By combining the powerful logging capabilities of Splunk Platform with Splunk Observability Cloud’s traces and real-time metrics for deeper insights and more context of your hybrid environment.
Perform quick and easy log-based investigations: By reusing logs that are already ingested in Splunk Cloud Platform or Enterprise in a simplified and intuitive interface (no need to know SPL!) with customizable and out-of-the-box dashboards
Achieve higher economies of scale and operational efficiency: By centralizing log management across teams, breaking down data and team silos, and getting better overall support</description></item><item><title>Synthetics Overview</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.70/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/5-synthetics-home/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.70/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/5-synthetics-home/index.html</guid><description>Splunk Synthetic Monitoring provides visibility across URLs, APIs and critical web services to solve problems faster. IT Operations and engineering teams can easily detect, alert and prioritize issues, simulate multi-step user journeys, measure business impact from new code deployments and optimize web performance with guided step-by-step recommendations to ensure better digital experiences.
Ensure Availability: Proactively monitor and alert on the health and availability of critical services, URLs and APIs with customizable browser tests to simulate multi-step workflows that make up the user experience.
Improve Metrics: Core Web Vitals and modern performance metrics allow users to view all their performance defects in one place, measure and improve page load, interactivity and visual stability, and find and fix JavaScript errors to improve page performance.
front-end to back-end: Integrations with Splunk APM, Infrastructure Monitoring, On-Call and ITSI help teams view endpoint uptime against back-end services, the underlying infrastructure and within their incident response coordination so they can troubleshoot across their entire environment, in a single UI.
Detect and Alert: Monitor and simulate end-user experiences to detect, communicate and resolve issues for APIs, service endpoints and critical business transactions before they impact customers.
Business Performance: Easily define multi-step user flows for key business transactions and start recording and testing your critical user journeys in minutes. Track and report SLAs and SLOs for uptime and performance.
Filmstrips and Video Playback: View screen recordings, film strips, and screenshots alongside modern performance scores, competitive benchmarking, and metrics to visualize artificial end-user experiences. Optimize how fast you deliver visual content, and improve page stability and interactivity to deploy better digital experiences.</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure Overview</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.70/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/6-infrastructure-home/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.70/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/6-infrastructure-home/index.html</guid><description>Splunk Infrastructure Monitoring (IM) is a market-leading monitoring and observability service for hybrid cloud environments. Built on a patented streaming architecture, it provides a real-time solution for engineering teams to visualize and analyze performance across infrastructure, services, and applications in a fraction of the time and with greater accuracy than traditional solutions.
OpenTelemetry standardization: Gives you full control over your data — freeing you from vendor lock-in and implementing proprietary agents.
Splunk’s OTel Collector: Seamless installation and dynamic configuration, auto-discovers your entire stack in seconds for visibility across clouds, services, and systems.
300+ Easy-to-use OOTB content: Pre-built navigators and dashboards, deliver immediate visualizations of your entire environment so that you can interact with all your data in real time.
Kubernetes navigator: Provides an instant, comprehensive out-of-the-box hierarchical view of nodes, pods, and containers. Ramp up even the most novice Kubernetes user with easy-to-understand interactive cluster maps.
AutoDetect alerts and detectors: Automatically identify the most important metrics, out-of-the-box, to create alert conditions for detectors that accurately alert from the moment telemetry data is ingested and use real-time alerting capabilities for important notifications in seconds.
Log views in dashboards: Combine log messages and real-time metrics on one page with common filters and time controls for faster in-context troubleshooting.
Metrics pipeline management: Control metrics volume at the point of ingest without re-instrumentation with a set of aggregation and data-dropping rules to store and analyze only the needed data. Reduce metrics volume and optimize observability spend.</description></item></channel></rss>