<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Workshop Setup :: Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.71/en/workshop-setup/index.html</link><description>Welcome to the Observability Workshop Setup Guide. This guide will walk you through the steps required to set up your workshop environments.
Provided Orgs (Splunk Employees Only) Existing Workshop Orgs:
The following Organizations can be used by Splunkers for running Observability Workshops. They have all the features enabled to successfully run any of the available workshops: CoE Workshop EMEA (EU0) Observability Workshop EMEA (EU0) Observability Workshop AMER (US1) APAC-O11y-Workshop (US1) Blacklisted Orgs:</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.71/en/workshop-setup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1. Using SWiPE</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.71/en/workshop-setup/1-swipe/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.71/en/workshop-setup/1-swipe/index.html</guid><description>Configure Your Org Using SWiPE SWiPE is an online tool to help configure a workshop environment in Splunk Observability Cloud and is available here.
Info SWiPE does not provision EC2 instances - these are provisioned using Splunk Show.
SWiPE will configure the following:
Create and invite users to the Org. Create a .csv file containing the e-mail addresses (one per line) or copy and paste e-mail addresses (one per line). If Ninja Workshop is enabled, then the users will be provisioned with Admin access control. If Override HEC URL and Token is enabled, then a custom HEC URL and Token can be configured to override the default values which are used for sending logs to Splunk. Create a team and add users to the team. Create a SWiPE ID for use in Splunk Show. You will need to copy the SWiPE ID to provision the workshop instance(s) in Splunk Show. Warning If you have more than 40 users in your workshop, we suggest informing the support team to ensure the trial or workshop environment is properly scaled.</description></item><item><title>2. Using Splunk Show</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.71/en/workshop-setup/2-splunk-show/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.71/en/workshop-setup/2-splunk-show/index.html</guid><description>Provision the EC2 Instances Using Splunk Show Please visit Splunk Show to provision your workshop instance(s).
Select the desired Content Type as follows:
Pre-configured Instances - select this if you need the OpenTelemetry Collector and the application pre-deployed for a less technical audience. Attendees will only require a browser to complete the workshop. This option must be selected if you want to run the Splunk4Rookies - Observability Cloud Workshop.</description></item><item><title>3. Workshop Clean-up</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.71/en/workshop-setup/3-clean-up/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.71/en/workshop-setup/3-clean-up/index.html</guid><description>Workshop Clean-up Once you have completed your workshop session please remember to go back and clean up the environment using SWiPE. Also, ensure your workshop instances are deleted to save costs.
SWiPE will complete the following:
Delete all the users associated with the workshop Delete the team Delete the tokens (INGEST, API and RUM) Delete user dashboards</description></item><item><title>4. Trial Org Configuration</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.71/en/workshop-setup/4-org-configuration/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.71/en/workshop-setup/4-org-configuration/index.html</guid><description>Log Observer Connect The workshops require a Log Observer Connect configuration to be setup. This is required to be able to send logs from the workshop instances to Splunk Cloud/Enterprise. SWiPE provides a simple form to configure this and is available here.
Log Field Aliasing Log Field Aliasing configuration is required to ensure Related Content works correctly in the Splunk Observability Cloud UI. Configure as per the following:</description></item></channel></rss>