<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Correlate Metrics and Logs on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.49/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/4-correlate-metrics-logs/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Correlate Metrics and Logs on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.49/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/4-correlate-metrics-logs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Correlate Metrics and Logs</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.49/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/4-correlate-metrics-logs/1-correlate-metrics-and-logs/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.49/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/4-correlate-metrics-logs/1-correlate-metrics-and-logs/index.html</guid><description>In this section, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive into the seamless correlation of metrics and logs facilitated by the robust naming standards offered by OpenTelemetry. By harnessing the power of OpenTelemetry within Splunk Observability Cloud, we&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how troubleshooting issues becomes significantly more efficient for Site Reliability Engineers (SREs) and operators. With this integration, contextualizing data across various telemetry sources no longer demands manual effort to correlate information. Instead, SREs and operators gain immediate access to the pertinent context they need, allowing them to swiftly pinpoint and resolve issues, improving system reliability and performance.</description></item><item><title>Create Log-based Chart</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.49/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/4-correlate-metrics-logs/2-create-log-based-chart/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.49/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/4-correlate-metrics-logs/2-create-log-based-chart/index.html</guid><description>In Log Observer, you can perform codeless queries on logs to detect the source of problems in your systems. You can also extract fields from logs to set up log processing rules and transform your data as it arrives or send data to Infinite Logging S3 buckets for future use. See What can I do with Log Observer? to learn more about Log Observer capabilities.
In this section, you&amp;rsquo;ll create a chart filtered to logs that include errors which will be added to the K8s Pod Dashboard you cloned in section 3.</description></item></channel></rss>