<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RUM on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/tags/rum/index.html</link><description>Recent content in RUM on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/tags/rum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1. RUM Dashboard</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/6-rum/1-rum-dashboard/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/6-rum/1-rum-dashboard/index.html</guid><description>In Splunk Observability Cloud from the main menu, click on RUM. From the drop-downs ensure the following is set/selected:
Timeframe is set to -15m. Environment selected is [NAME OF WORKSHOP]-workshop. App selected is [NAME OF WORKSHOP]-shop. Source is set to All. This view has already been covered in the short introduction earlier. Next, click on the [NAME OF WORKSHOP]-workshop above the Page Views / JavaScript Errors chart.
This will bring up a dashboard view breaking down the metrics by UX Metrics, Front-end Health, Back-end Health and Custom Events.</description></item><item><title>Splunk4Rookies - Observability</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/index.html</guid><description>In this workshop, we will be showing how Splunk Observability Cloud provides instant visibility of the user experience – from the perspective of the front-end application to its back-end services – showing off some of the most compelling product features and differentiators of the Splunk Observability Cloud Suite:
Infrastructure Monitoring Full-fidelity Real User Monitoring (RUM) Complete end-to-end NoSample™ Full-fidelity trace visibility with Application Performance Monitoring (APM) No code log querying Synthetic Monitoring Finding root causes with tag analytics and error stacks Related content One core tenet in building the Splunk Observability Cloud is to unify telemetry data to create a complete picture of an end-user experience and your application stack.</description></item></channel></rss>