<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Splunk4Rookies - Observability on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Splunk4Rookies - Observability on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Workshop Overview</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/1-workshop-goals/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/1-workshop-goals/index.html</guid><description>1. Introduction The goal of this workshop is to experience an issue and use Splunk Observability Cloud to troubleshoot and identify the root cause. For this, we have provided a complete microservices-based application running in Kubernetes that has been instrumented to send metrics, traces, and logs to Splunk Observability Cloud.
2. OpenTelemetry A Quick introduction to why OpenTelemetry and why is it important for Observability.
3. A tour of the Splunk Observability User Interface A walkthrough of the various components of Splunk Observability Cloud showing you how to easily navigate the 5 main components:- Infrastructure, RUM, APM, Logs, and Synthetics.</description></item><item><title>What is OpenTelemetry?</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/2-opentelemetry/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/2-opentelemetry/index.html</guid><description>With the rise of cloud computing, microservices architectures, and ever-more complex business requirements, the need for Observability has never been greater. Observability is the ability to understand the internal state of a system by examining its outputs. In the context of software, this means being able to understand the internal state of a system by examining its telemetry data, which includes metrics, traces, and logs.
To make a system observable, it must be instrumented.</description></item><item><title>UI - Quick Tour</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/3-initial-tour/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/3-initial-tour/index.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Infrastructure Exercise</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/4-im-exercise/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/4-im-exercise/index.html</guid><description>5 minutes This is the first section of our Kubernetes Navigator exercise. Below is some high-level information regarding Kubernetes, just in case you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar with it.
Kubernetes Terminology K8s, short for Kubernetes, is an open-source container orchestration platform. It manages the deployment, scaling, and maintenance of containerized applications, and we use it in this workshop to host our e-commerce application
Some terminology:
A Kubernetes cluster is a group of machines, called nodes, that work together to run containerized applications.</description></item><item><title>5. Shopping at the Online Boutique</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/5-online-boutique/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/5-online-boutique/index.html</guid><description>The purpose of this exercise is for you to interact with the Online Boutique web application. This is a sample application that is used to demonstrate the capabilities of Splunk Observability Cloud. The application is a simple e-commerce site that allows you to browse items, add them to your cart, and then checkout.
The application will already be deployed for you and your instructor will provide you with a link to the Online Boutique website.</description></item><item><title>Real User Monitoring Exercise</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/6-rum/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/6-rum/index.html</guid><description>We are going to examine the real user data that has been provided by the telemetry received from all participants&amp;rsquo; browser sessions. The goal is to find a browser, mobile or tablet session that performed poorly and begin the troubleshooting process.</description></item><item><title>Splunk APM</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/7-apm/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/7-apm/index.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Splunk Log Observer</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/8-log-observer/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/8-log-observer/index.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Splunk Synthetics</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/9-synthetics/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/9-synthetics/index.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>War Room Dashboard</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/10-war-room/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/10-war-room/index.html</guid><description>WIP WIP WIP WIP WIP</description></item><item><title>Workshop Wrap-up</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/11-wrap-up/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.13/en/s4r/11-wrap-up/index.html</guid><description>This wraps up the Splunk for Rookies Workshop of the Splunk Observability Cloud. We were able to:
Understand what real users were experiencing See how we can detect these issues through Detectors, Dashboards and Synthetic Tests Troubleshoot a particularly long page load, by following its trace across the front and back end and right to the log entries. Use Tag Spotlight, in both RUM and APM, to understand blast radius and context for our performance issues and errors.</description></item></channel></rss>