<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Optimize End User Experiences on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Optimize End User Experiences on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Synthetics</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/1-synthetics/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/1-synthetics/index.html</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s quickly set up some tests in Synthetics to immediately start understanding our end user experience, without waiting for real users to interact with our app.
We can capture not only the performance and availability of our own apps and endpoints, but also those third parties we rely on any time of the day or night.
Tip If you find that your tests are being bot-blocked, see the docs for tips on how to allow Synthetic testing.</description></item><item><title>RUM</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/2-rum/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/2-rum/index.html</guid><description>With RUM instrumented, we will be able to better understand our end users, what they are doing, and what issues they are encountering.
This workshop walks through how our demo site is instrumented and how to interpret the data. If you already have a RUM license, this will help you understand how RUM works and how you can use it to optimize your end user experience.
Tip Our Docs also contain guidance such as scenarios using Splunk RUM and demo applications to test out RUM for mobile apps.</description></item><item><title>Advanced Synthetics</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/3-advanced-synthetics/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/3-advanced-synthetics/index.html</guid><description>Introduction This workshop walks you through using the Chrome DevTools Recorder to create a synthetic test on a Splunk demonstration environment or on your own public website.
The exported JSON from the Chrome DevTools Recorder will then be used to create a Splunk Synthetic Monitoring Real Browser Test.
Pre-requisites Google Chrome Browser installed Publicly browser-accessible URL Access to Splunk Observability Cloud Supporting resources Lantern: advanced Selectors for multi-step browser tests Chrome for Developers DevTools Tips web.</description></item><item><title>Frontend Dashboards</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/4-dashboards/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/4-dashboards/index.html</guid><description>Go to Dashboards and find the End User Experiences dashboard group.
Click the three dots on the top right to open the dashboard menu, and select Save As, and include your team name and initials in the dashboard name.
Save to the dashboard group that matches your email address. Now you have your own copy of this dashboard to customize!</description></item><item><title>Detectors</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/5-detectors/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/5-detectors/index.html</guid><description>After we have a good understanding of our performance baseline, we can start to create Detectors so that we receive alerts when our KPIs are unexpected. If we create detectors before understanding our baseline, we run the risk of generating unnecessary alert noise.
For RUM and Synthetics, we will explore how to create detectors:
on a single Synthetic test on a single KPI in RUM on a dashboard chart For more Detector resources, please see our Observability docs, Lantern, and consider an Education course if you&amp;rsquo;d like to go more in depth with instructor guidance.</description></item><item><title>Summary</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/6-summary/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/6-summary/index.html</guid><description>In this workshop, we learned the following:
How to create simple synthetic tests so that we can quickly begin to understand the availability and performance of our application How to understand what RUM shows us about the end user experience, including specific user sessions How to write advanced synthetic browser tests to proactively test our most important user actions How to visualize our frontend performance data in context with events on dashboards How to set up detectors so we don&amp;rsquo;t have to wait to hear about issues from our end users How all of the above, plus Splunk and Google&amp;rsquo;s resources, helps us optimize end user experience There is a lot more we can do with front end performance monitoring.</description></item><item><title>Workshop Setup and Cleanup</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/setup/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/setup/index.html</guid><description>Please follow these steps for the Optimize End User Experiences workshop setup, &amp;ldquo;behind the scenes&amp;rdquo; instructions during the workshop, and cleanup.
Before the workshop See instructions on using SWiPE for provisioning. Come up with a simple team name that your attendees will use when naming dashboards, detectors, and synthetic tests. This is intended to help you during cleanup later. For example, a specific dog breed, flower name, etc. Remind attendees throughout the workshop to include the team name and their initials when they are creating asset names.</description></item></channel></rss>