<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Observability 4 Rookies on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.90/en/other/o11y4rookies/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Observability 4 Rookies on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.90/en/other/o11y4rookies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Splunk IM</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.90/en/other/o11y4rookies/imt/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.90/en/other/o11y4rookies/imt/index.html</guid><description>In order to simplify the overall experience we will provide you hands on deck to the actual environment where we have the Online Boutique store instrumented via Splunk. This application is written in Java and has microservice architecture
The workshops also introduce you to dashboards, editing and creating charts, creating detectors to fire alerts, Monitoring as Code and the Service Bureau[^6]
By the end of these technical workshops you will have a good understanding of some of the key features and capabilities of the Splunk Observability Cloud.</description></item><item><title>Splunk APM</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.90/en/other/o11y4rookies/apm/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.90/en/other/o11y4rookies/apm/index.html</guid><description>Splunk APM is a NoSample™ Full-fidelity application performance monitoring and troubleshooting solution for cloud-native, microservices-based applications.
By collecting all traces, instead of a sampled subset, no anomaly goes undetected. Whether a user experiences an error or longer-than-usual latency, you’ll be able to know and act on it within seconds. Furthermore, not all bad behavior results in errors — as your developers create new applications they need to know whether their canary releases provide the expected results.</description></item><item><title>Splunk RUM</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.90/en/other/o11y4rookies/rum/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.90/en/other/o11y4rookies/rum/index.html</guid><description>Splunk RUM is the industry’s only end to end, full fidelity Real User Monitoring solution. It is built to optimize performance and aid in faster troubleshooting, giving you full visibility into end-user experiences.
Splunk RUM allows you to identify performance problems in your Web and or Mobile applications that impact the customer experience. We support benchmarking and measuring page performance with core web vitals. This includes but not limited to: W3C timings, the ability to identify long running tasks, along with everything that can impact your page load.</description></item><item><title>Splunk Synthetics</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.90/en/other/o11y4rookies/synthetics/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.90/en/other/o11y4rookies/synthetics/index.html</guid><description>Splunk Synthetic Monitoring offers the most comprehensive and in-depth capabilities for uptime and web performance optimization as part of the only complete observability suite, Splunk Observability Cloud.
Easily set up monitoring for APIs, service endpoints and end-user-experience. With Splunk Synthetic monitoring, go beyond basic uptime and performance monitoring and focus on proactively finding and fixing issues, optimizing web performance, and ensuring customers get the best user experience.
With Splunk Synthetic Monitoring you can:</description></item></channel></rss>