<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Splunk APM on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.14/en/s4r/7-apm/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Splunk APM on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.14/en/s4r/7-apm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1. APM Overview</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.14/en/s4r/7-apm/1-apm-overview/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.14/en/s4r/7-apm/1-apm-overview/index.html</guid><description>The service map displays the dependencies and connections among your instrumented and inferred services in APM. The map is dynamically generated based on your selections in the time range, environment, workflow, service, and tag filters.
When we clicked on the APM link in the RUM waterfall, filters were automatically added to the service map view to show the services that were involved in that particular trace.
You can use the service map to identify dependencies, performance bottlenecks, and error propagation.</description></item><item><title>2. APM Explore</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.14/en/s4r/7-apm/2-apm-explore/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.14/en/s4r/7-apm/2-apm-explore/index.html</guid><description>From the Overview Page, click on Explore on the top right of the page. You will be presented with the full service map which now includes all services (including inferred services). Inferred services are visually represented by a dotted outline.
Exercise How many services are there in total? Click on the mysql:LxvGChW075 inferred service. Under Database Query Performance click on the top entry. This will take you to the Database Query Performance page.</description></item><item><title>3. APM Tag Spotlight</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.14/en/s4r/7-apm/3-apm-tag-spotlight/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.14/en/s4r/7-apm/3-apm-tag-spotlight/index.html</guid><description>To view the tags for the paymentservice click on the paymentservice and then click on Tag Spotlight. Once in Tag Spotlight ensure the toggle Show tags with no values is off.
There are two views available in Tag Spotlight. The default is Request/Errors and the other is Latency.
Request/Error charts display the total number of requests, errors, and root cause errors. The Latency charts display p50, p90, and p99 latency. These values are based on Troubleshooting MetricSets (TMS), which Splunk APM generates for every indexed span tag.</description></item><item><title>4. APM Service Breakdown</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.14/en/s4r/7-apm/4-apm-service-breakdown/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.14/en/s4r/7-apm/4-apm-service-breakdown/index.html</guid><description> Click on the payment service and then from breakdown select version You can see all errors are due to v350.10</description></item><item><title>5. APM Trace Analyzer</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.14/en/s4r/7-apm/5-apm-trace-analyzer/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.14/en/s4r/7-apm/5-apm-trace-analyzer/index.html</guid><description> Click on traces Click on Group traces by and select version Click on elipsis next to v350.10 and click add to filter. Sort traces by duration Select the 1st trace ensuring it has a long duration</description></item><item><title>6. APM Waterfall</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.14/en/s4r/7-apm/6-apm-waterfall/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.14/en/s4r/7-apm/6-apm-waterfall/index.html</guid><description> What can you conclude is going on from the waterfall? (Answer multiple attempts) Verify version is v350.10 by looking at the metadata under tags. Conclusion &amp;hellip; we have a problem. Draw attention to related content &amp;hellip; TBC Click on Logs for trace XXXXXXX</description></item></channel></rss>