<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Service Bureau on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.31/en/imt/servicebureau/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Service Bureau on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.31/en/imt/servicebureau/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Teams</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.31/en/imt/servicebureau/teams/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.31/en/imt/servicebureau/teams/index.html</guid><description>Introduction to Teams Create a Team and add members to Team 1. Introduction to Teams To make sure that users see the dashboards and alerts that are relevant to them when using Observability Cloud, most organizations will use Observability Cloud&amp;rsquo;s Teams feature to assign a member to one or more Teams.
Ideally, this matches work related roles, for example, members of a Dev-Ops or Product Management group would be assigned to the corresponding Teams in Observability Cloud.</description></item><item><title>Controlling Usage</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.31/en/imt/servicebureau/tokens/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.31/en/imt/servicebureau/tokens/index.html</guid><description>Discover how you can restrict usage by creating separate Access Tokens and set limits. 1. Access Tokens If you wish to control the consumption of Hosts, Containers, Custom Metrics and High Resolution Metrics, you can create multiple Access Tokens and allocate them to different parts of your organization.
In the UI click on the &amp;raquo; bottom left and select the Settings → Access Tokens under General Settings.
The Access Tokens Interface provides an overview of your allotments in the form of a list of Access Tokens that have been generated.</description></item></channel></rss>