<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>.conf23 Workshops on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.93/en/conf/index.html</link><description>Recent content in .conf23 Workshops on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.93/en/conf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Making Your Observability Cloud Native With OpenTelemetry</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.93/en/conf/opentelemetry-collector/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.93/en/conf/opentelemetry-collector/index.html</guid><description>Abstract Organizations getting started with OpenTelemetry may begin by sending data directly to an observability backend. While this works well for initial testing, using the OpenTelemetry collector as part of your observability architecture provides numerous benefits and is recommended for any production deployment.
In this workshop, we will be focusing on using the OpenTelemetry collector and starting with the fundamentals of configuring the receivers, processors, and exporters ready to use with Splunk Observability Cloud.</description></item><item><title>Digital Experience Monitoring (DEM)</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.93/en/conf/dem/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.93/en/conf/dem/index.html</guid><description>Objective: Understand end user experience through RUM and Synthetics, and how to improve that experience in the front end.
You need:
Access to the Workshop Org in Splunk Observability Cloud Outline:
Understand the context: what are RUM and Synthetics? Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to get hands on! Navigate the website and see results in RUM Create a Synthetic browser test Dashboards and detectors How do you compete? Advanced: multi-step browser tests Bonus: Web Optimization</description></item></channel></rss>