<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Working with Dashboards on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.34/en/imt/dashboards/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Working with Dashboards on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.34/en/imt/dashboards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Editing charts</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.34/en/imt/dashboards/editing/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.34/en/imt/dashboards/editing/index.html</guid><description>1. Editing a chart Select the SAMPLE CHARTS dashboard and then click on the three dots ... on the Latency histogram chart, then on Open (or you can click on the name of the chart which here is Latency histogram).
You will see the plot options, current plot and signal (metric) for the Latency histogram chart in the chart editor UI.
In the Plot Editor tab under Signal you see the metric demo.</description></item><item><title>Saving charts</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.34/en/imt/dashboards/savingcharts/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.34/en/imt/dashboards/savingcharts/index.html</guid><description>1. Saving a chart To start saving your chart, lets give it a name and description. Click the name of the chart Copy of Latency Histogram and rename it to &amp;ldquo;Active Latency&amp;rdquo;.
To change the description click on Spread of latency values across time. and change this to Overview of latency values in real-time.
Click the Save As button. Make sure your chart has a name, it will use the name Active Latency the you defined in the previous step, but you can edit it here if needed.</description></item><item><title>3.3 Using Filters &amp; Formulas</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.34/en/imt/dashboards/filtering/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.34/en/imt/dashboards/filtering/index.html</guid><description>1 Creating a new chart Let&amp;rsquo;s now create a new chart and save it in our dashboard!
Select the plus icon (top right of the UI) and from the drop down, choose the option Chart. Or click on the + New Chart Button to create a new chart.
You will now see a chart template like the following.
Let&amp;rsquo;s enter a metric to plot. We are still going to use the metric demo.</description></item><item><title>3.4 SignalFlow</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.34/en/imt/dashboards/signalflow/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.34/en/imt/dashboards/signalflow/index.html</guid><description>1. Introduction Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at SignalFlow - the analytics language of Observability Cloud that can be used to setup monitoring as code.
The heart of Splunk Infrastructure Monitoring is the SignalFlow analytics engine that runs computations written in a Python-like language. SignalFlow programs accept streaming input and produce output in real time. SignalFlow provides built-in analytical functions that take metric time series (MTS) as input, perform computations, and output a resulting MTS.</description></item><item><title>Adding charts to dashboards</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.34/en/imt/dashboards/adding-charts/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.34/en/imt/dashboards/adding-charts/index.html</guid><description>1. Save to existing dashboard Check that you have YOUR_NAME-Dashboard: YOUR_NAME-Dashboard in the top left corner. This means you chart will be saved in this Dashboard.
Name the Chart Latency History and add a Chart Description if you wish.
Click on Save And Close . This returns you to your dashboard that now has two charts!
Now let&amp;rsquo;s quickly add another Chart based on the previous one.
2. Copy and Paste a chart Click on the three dots .</description></item><item><title>Adding Notes and Dashboard Layout</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.34/en/imt/dashboards/notes-and-layout/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.34/en/imt/dashboards/notes-and-layout/index.html</guid><description>1. Adding Notes Often on dashboards it makes sense to place a short &amp;ldquo;instruction&amp;rdquo; pane that helps users of a dashboard. Lets add one now by clicking on the New Text Note Button.
This will open the notes editor.
To allow you to add more then just text to you notes, Splunk is allowing you to use Markdown in these notes/panes. Markdown is a lightweight markup language for creating formatted text using plain-text often used in Webpages.</description></item></channel></rss>