<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Improve Timeliness of Alerts :: Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.71/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/5-improve-alert-timeliness/index.html</link><description>When monitoring hybrid and cloud environments, ensuring timely alerts for critical infrastructure and applications poses a significant challenge. Typically, this involves crafting intricate queries, meticulously scheduling searches, and managing alerts across various monitoring solutions. Moreover, the proliferation of disparate alerts generated from identical data sources often results in unnecessary duplication, contributing to alert fatigue and noise within the monitoring ecosystem.
In this section, we’ll explore how Splunk Observability Cloud addresses these challenges by enabling the effortless creation of alert criteria. Leveraging its 10-second default data collection capability, alerts can be triggered swiftly, surpassing the timeliness achieved by traditional monitoring tools. This enhanced responsiveness not only reduces Mean Time to Detect (MTTD) but also accelerates Mean Time to Resolve (MTTR), ensuring that critical issues are promptly identified and remediated.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.71/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/5-improve-alert-timeliness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create Custom Detector</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.71/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/5-improve-alert-timeliness/1-create-custom-detector/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.71/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/5-improve-alert-timeliness/1-create-custom-detector/index.html</guid><description>Splunk Observability Cloud provides detectors, events, alerts, and notifications to keep you informed when certain criteria are met. There are a number of pre-built AutoDetect Detectors that automatically surface when common problem patterns occur, such as when an EC2 instance’s CPU utilization is expected to reach its limit. Additionally, you can also create custom detectors if you want something more optimized or specific. For example, you want a message sent to a Slack channel or to an email address for the Ops team that manages this Kubernetes cluster when Memory Utilization on their pods has reached 85%.</description></item></channel></rss>