<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Frontend Dashboards :: Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.71/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/4-dashboards/index.html</link><description>Go to Dashboards and find the End User Experiences dashboard group.
Click the three dots on the top right to open the dashboard menu, and select Save As, and include your team name and initials in the dashboard name.
Save to the dashboard group that matches your email address. Now you have your own copy of this dashboard to customize!</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.71/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/4-dashboards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Copying and editing charts</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.71/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/4-dashboards/1-copying-charts/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.71/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/4-dashboards/1-copying-charts/index.html</guid><description>We have some good charts in our dashboard, but let’s add a few more.
Go to Dashboards by clicking the dasboard icon on the left side of the screen. Find the Browser app health dashboard and scroll to the Largest Contentful Paint (LCP) chart. Click the chart actions icon to open the flyout menu, and click “Copy” to add this chart to your clipboard.</description></item><item><title>Events in context with chart data</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.71/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/4-dashboards/2-event-overlay/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.71/en/scenarios/optimize_end_user_experiences/4-dashboards/2-event-overlay/index.html</guid><description>Seeing the visualization of our KPIs is great. What’s better? KPIs in context with events! Overlaying events on a dashboard can help us more quickly understand if an event like a deployment caused a change in metrics, for better or worse.
Your instructor will push a condition change to the workshop application. Click the event marker on any of your dashboard charts to see more details.</description></item></channel></rss>