<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Splunk4Rookies - Observability on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Splunk4Rookies - Observability on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Workshop Overview</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/1-workshop-goals/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/1-workshop-goals/index.html</guid><description>1. Introduction The goal of this workshop is to experience an issue and use Splunk Observability Cloud to troubleshoot the issue and identify the route cause. For this we have provided you with a complete application that includes a frontend and a number of backend services that have been instrumented to send metrics, traces and logs.
2. A quick tour of the Splunk Observability User Interface We will take you through the various components of the Splunk Observability Suite, and show you how to easily navigate the 5 main components (Infrastructure, RUM, APM, Logs and Synthetics).</description></item><item><title>Connecting to the Splunk observability UI</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/2-initial-tour/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/2-initial-tour/index.html</guid><description>5 minutes The goal of this section is to make you comfortable with the UI of Splunk Observability Cloud. We first need to log in, then we can examine the main components of the UI, followed by a couple of exercise&amp;rsquo;s to get you started.
1. Login in to Splunk Observability Cloud Your instructor may already have told you that you should have received an e-mail from Splunk that invites you to the Workshop Org (org is short for Organization).</description></item><item><title>Shopping at the Online Boutique</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/4-online-boutique/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/4-online-boutique/index.html</guid><description>The purpose of this exercise is for you to interact with the Online Boutique web application. This is a sample application that is used to demonstrate the capabilities of Splunk Observability Cloud. The application is a simple e-commerce site that allows you to browse items, add them to your cart, and then checkout.
The application will already be deployed for you and your instructor will provide you with a link to the Online Boutique website.</description></item><item><title>Splunk RUM</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/5-rum/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/5-rum/index.html</guid><description>Splunk RUM is the industry’s only end-to-end, NoSample™ RUM solution - providing visibility into the full user experience of every web and mobile session to uniquely combine all front-end traces with back-end metrics, traces, and logs as they happen. IT Operations and Engineering teams can quickly scope, prioritize and isolate errors, measure how performance impacts real users and optimize end-user experiences by correlating performance metrics alongside video reconstructions of all user interactions.</description></item><item><title>Splunk APM</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/6-apm/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/6-apm/index.html</guid><description>Splunk APM provides a NoSample™ end-to-end visibility of every service and its dependency to solve problems quicker across monoliths and microservices. Teams can immediately detect problems from new deployments, confidently troubleshoot by scoping and isolating the source of an issue, and optimize service performance by understanding how backend services impact end users and business workflows.
Real-time monitoring and alerting: Splunk provides a 10 second resolution on metrics to detect and alert on issues when they happen.</description></item><item><title>Splunk Log Observer Connect</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/7-log-observer/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/7-log-observer/index.html</guid><description>Log Observer Connect allows you to seamlessly bring in the same log data from your Splunk Platform into an intuitive and codeless interface designed to help you find and fix problems fast. You can easily perform log-based analysis and seamlessly correlate your logs with Splunk Infrastructure Monitoring’s real-time metrics and Splunk APM traces in one place.
End-to-end visibility: By combining the powerful logging capabilities of Splunk Platform with Splunk Observability Cloud’s traces and real-time metrics for deeper insights and more context of your hybrid environment.</description></item><item><title>Automate testing your application with Splunk Synthetics</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/8-synthetics/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/8-synthetics/index.html</guid><description>Splunk Synthetic Monitoring provides visibility across URLs, APIs and critical web services to solve problems faster. IT Operations and engineering teams can easily detect, alert and prioritize issues, simulate multi-step user journeys, measure business impact from new code deployments and optimize web performance with guided step-by-step recommendations to ensure better digital experiences.
Ensure Availability: Proactively monitor and alert on the health and availability of critical services, URLs and APIs with customizable browser tests to simulate multi-step workflows that make up the user experience.</description></item><item><title>Splunk Infrastructure exercise with the Kubernetes Navigator</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/3-navigator-maybe-deleted/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/3-navigator-maybe-deleted/index.html</guid><description>TBD
Navigate to the K8s Navigator &amp;hellip; walk through &amp;hellip; filtering, metrics, node dependencies, etc.
Talk around what has been deployed
Talk around initial panes goto Nodes Filter to workshop cluster Review default metrics Node dependencies Click on mysql pod Talk around metadata for the container Back to Infrastructure Something to trigger alerts in Navigator?</description></item><item><title>Workshop Wrap-up</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/9-wrap-up/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/9-wrap-up/index.html</guid><description>This wraps up the Splunk for Rookies Workshop of the Splunk Observability Cloud. We were able to:
Understand what real users were experiencing Saw how we can detect these issue though Detectors, Dashboards and Synthetic Tests Troubleshoot a particularly long page load, by following it’s trace across the front and back end and right to the log entries Use tag spotlight, in both RUM and APM, to understand blast radius and context for our performance issues and errors Today we didn’t even talk about the power of the rest of Splunk Observability Cloud, such as:</description></item></channel></rss>