<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Infrastructure Exercise 1 on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/2-initial-tour/im-exercise/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Infrastructure Exercise 1 on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/2-initial-tour/im-exercise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Splunk Infrastructure exercise with the Kubernetes Navigator</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/2-initial-tour/im-exercise/1-im-excersise/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/2-initial-tour/im-exercise/1-im-excersise/index.html</guid><description>8 minutes This is the second section, of the infra monitoring exercise, You should now have your single cluster visible.
In the Kubernetes Navigator, your cluster is represented by the square with the black line, it will contain one or more blue squares representing the node(s), each of them wil contain one or more colored boxes that represent pods. and as you can guess, Green means healthy &amp;amp; Red means that there is a problem.</description></item><item><title>Splunk Infrastructure exercise with the Kubernetes Navigator</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/2-initial-tour/im-exercise/2-im-excersise/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.11/en/s4r/2-initial-tour/im-exercise/2-im-excersise/index.html</guid><description>6 minutes We are now going to work with the Information Pane on the right of the navigator.
This pane provides alert information, info on detected services and shows meta data related to the object your looking at, in this case a kubernetes node running on an ec2 instance in AWS.
Exercise Meta Data is send along wth the metrics an are very useful to identify trends when identifying issues.</description></item></channel></rss>