<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>UI - Quick Tour 🚌 on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/index.html</link><description>Recent content in UI - Quick Tour 🚌 on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Started</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/1-homepage/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/1-homepage/index.html</guid><description>2 minutes 1. Sign in to Splunk Observability Cloud You should have received an e-mail from Splunk inviting you to the Workshop Org. This e-mail will look like the screenshot below, if you cannot find it, please check your Spam/Junk folders or inform your Instructor. You can also check for other solutions in our login F.A.Q..
To proceed click the Join Now button or click on the link provided in the e-mail.</description></item><item><title>Real User Monitoring Overview</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/2-rum-home/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/2-rum-home/index.html</guid><description>5 minutes Splunk RUM is the industry’s only end-to-end, NoSample™ RUM solution - providing visibility into the full user experience of every web and mobile session to uniquely combine all front-end traces with back-end metrics, traces, and logs as they happen. IT Operations and Engineering teams can quickly scope, prioritize and isolate errors, measure how performance impacts real users and optimize end-user experiences by correlating performance metrics alongside video reconstructions of all user interactions.</description></item><item><title>Application Performance Monitoring Overview</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/3-apm-home/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/3-apm-home/index.html</guid><description>5 minutes Splunk APM provides a NoSample™ end-to-end visibility of every service and its dependency to solve problems quicker across monoliths and microservices. Teams can immediately detect problems from new deployments, confidently troubleshoot by scoping and isolating the source of an issue, and optimize service performance by understanding how back-end services impact end users and business workflows.
Real-time monitoring and alerting: Splunk provides out-of-the-box service dashboards and automatically detects and alerts on RED metrics (rate, error and duration) when there is a sudden change.</description></item><item><title>Log Observer Overview</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/4-log-observer-home/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/4-log-observer-home/index.html</guid><description>5 minutes Log Observer Connect allows you to seamlessly bring in the same log data from your Splunk Platform into an intuitive and no-code interface designed to help you find and fix problems quickly. You can easily perform log-based analysis and seamlessly correlate your logs with Splunk Infrastructure Monitoring’s real-time metrics and Splunk APM traces in one place.
End-to-end visibility: By combining the powerful logging capabilities of Splunk Platform with Splunk Observability Cloud’s traces and real-time metrics for deeper insights and more context of your hybrid environment.</description></item><item><title>Synthetics Overview</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/5-synthetics-home/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/5-synthetics-home/index.html</guid><description>5 minutes Splunk Synthetic Monitoring provides visibility across URLs, APIs and critical web services to solve problems faster. IT Operations and engineering teams can easily detect, alert and prioritize issues, simulate multi-step user journeys, measure business impact from new code deployments and optimize web performance with guided step-by-step recommendations to ensure better digital experiences.
Ensure Availability: Proactively monitor and alert on the health and availability of critical services, URLs and APIs with customizable browser tests to simulate multi-step workflows that make up the user experience.</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure Overview</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/6-infrastructure-home/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/6-infrastructure-home/index.html</guid><description>5 minutes Splunk Infrastructure Monitoring (IM) is a market-leading monitoring and observability service for hybrid cloud environments. Built on a patented streaming architecture, it provides a real-time solution for engineering teams to visualize and analyze performance across infrastructure, services, and applications in a fraction of the time and with greater accuracy than traditional solutions.
OpenTelemetry standardization: Gives you full control over your data — freeing you from vendor lock-in and implementing proprietary agents.</description></item></channel></rss>