<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Collect Data with Standards on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/scenarios/self_service_observability/2-collect_with_standards/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Collect Data with Standards on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/scenarios/self_service_observability/2-collect_with_standards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploy Gateway</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/scenarios/self_service_observability/2-collect_with_standards/1-deploy_gateway/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/scenarios/self_service_observability/2-collect_with_standards/1-deploy_gateway/index.html</guid><description>Gateway First we will deploy the OTel Gateway. The workshop instructor will deploy the gateway, but we will walk through the steps here if you wish to try this yourself on a second instance.
The steps:
Click the Data Management icon in the toolbar Click the + Add integration button Click Deploy the Splunk OpenTelemetry Collector button Click Next Select Linux Change mode to Data forwarding (gateway) Set the environment to prod Choose the access token for this workshop Click Next Copy the installer script and run it in the provided linux environment.</description></item><item><title>Deploy Collector (Agent)</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/scenarios/self_service_observability/2-collect_with_standards/2-deploy_collector_agent/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/scenarios/self_service_observability/2-collect_with_standards/2-deploy_collector_agent/index.html</guid><description>Collector (Agent) Now we will deploy a collector. At first this will be configured to go directly to the back-end, but we will change the configuration and restart the collector to use the gateway.
The steps:
Click the Data Management icon in the toolbar Click the + Add integration button Click Deploy the Splunk OpenTelemetry Collector button Click Next Select Linux Leave the mode as Host monitoring (agent) Set the environment to prod Leave the rest as defaults Choose the access token for this workshop Click Next Copy the installer script and run it in the provided linux environment.</description></item><item><title>Reconfigure Collector</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/scenarios/self_service_observability/2-collect_with_standards/3-reconfigure_collector/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/scenarios/self_service_observability/2-collect_with_standards/3-reconfigure_collector/index.html</guid><description>Reconfigure Collector To reconfigure the collector we need to make these changes:
In agent_config.yaml We need to adjust the signalfx exporter to use the gateway The otlp exporter is already there, so we leave it alone We need to change the pipelines to use otlp In splunk-otel-collector.conf We need to set the SPLUNK_GATEWAY_URL to the url provided by the instructor See this docs page for more details.
The exporters will be the following:</description></item></channel></rss>