<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Signing in to Splunk Observability Cloud on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.12/en/s4r/30-initial-tour/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Signing in to Splunk Observability Cloud on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.12/en/s4r/30-initial-tour/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Splunk Observability Cloud Home Page</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.12/en/s4r/30-initial-tour/1-homepage/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.12/en/s4r/30-initial-tour/1-homepage/index.html</guid><description>3 minutes After you have registered and logged into the Splunk Observability Cloud UI you will be taken to the home page. Here, you will find a number of useful features to help you get started.
Explore Data Pane: Displays which integrations are enabled and you can add additional integrations. Onboarding Pane: Training videos and links to documentation to get you started with Splunk Observability Cloud. Recent Pane: Recently created/visited dashboards and/or detectors for quick access.</description></item><item><title>Application Performance Monitoring Home page</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.12/en/s4r/30-initial-tour/2-apm-home/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.12/en/s4r/30-initial-tour/2-apm-home/index.html</guid><description>2 minutes Click APM in the main menu. The APM Home Page is made up of 3 distinct sections:
Onboarding Pane Pane: Training videos and links to documentation to get you started with Splunk APM. APM Overview Pane: Real-time metrics for the Top Services and Top Business Workflows. Functions Pane: Links for deeper analysis of your services, tags, traces, database query performance and code profiling. About Environments To easily differentiate between multiple applications, Splunk uses environments.</description></item><item><title>Real User Monitoring Home Page</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.12/en/s4r/30-initial-tour/3-rum-home-copy/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.12/en/s4r/30-initial-tour/3-rum-home-copy/index.html</guid><description>2 minutes Click APM in the main menu. The RUM Home Page is made up of 3 distinct sections:
Onboarding Pane: Training videos and links to documentation to get you started with Splunk RUM. Filter Pane: Filter on timeframe, environment, application and source type. Application Summary Pane: Summary of all your applications that send RUM data. Rum Environments &amp;amp; Apps As with APM, RUM uses environments that allow you to separate RUM trace information from different applications.</description></item><item><title>Checking Logs With Log Observer</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.12/en/s4r/30-initial-tour/4-log-observer/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.12/en/s4r/30-initial-tour/4-log-observer/index.html</guid><description>5 minutes We continue our tour of the Splunk Observability UI with Log Observer. Log Observer is a feature within Splunk Observability Cloud that allows you to seamlessly bring in log data from your Splunk Platform into an intuitive and codeless interface designed to help you find and fix problems quickly. You will be able to easily perform log-based analysis and seamlessly correlate your logs with Splunk Infrastructure Monitoring’s real-time metrics and Splunk APM traces in one place.</description></item><item><title>Splunk Synthetics Home Page</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.12/en/s4r/30-initial-tour/5-synthetics-home/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.12/en/s4r/30-initial-tour/5-synthetics-home/index.html</guid><description>5 minutes If you have not done so yet, select Splunk Synthetic from the menu bar on the right by selecting the (the robot icon) . This will bring us to the Synthetic Home Page. It has 3 distinct sections that provide either useful information or allow you to pick or create a Synthetic Test.
Onboarding Pane: Here you will find videos and information related to Splunk Synthetics. (Can be closed by pressing the X, if space is a premium) Test Pane: Here you find the list of all the tests that are active in your org, and you can select them to see the results.</description></item><item><title>Splunk Infrastructure &amp; Navigators</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.12/en/s4r/30-initial-tour/6-infrastructure-home/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.12/en/s4r/30-initial-tour/6-infrastructure-home/index.html</guid><description>5 minutes This section is split into multiple sections and is going to be a little longer, the first section is a quick intro to the main page, followed by a few sections to dive deeper into some of the special features of the Splunk Observability suite, before we start to use our application and validate performance.
Please select Splunk Infrastructure from the menu bar on the right by selecting the .</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure Exercise 1</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.12/en/s4r/30-initial-tour/7-im-exercise/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.12/en/s4r/30-initial-tour/7-im-exercise/index.html</guid><description>5 minutes This is the first section of our Kubernetes Navigator exercise. Below is some high-level information regarding Kubernetes, just in case you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar with it.
Kubernetes Terminology K8s, short for Kubernetes, is an open-source container orchestration platform. It manages the deployment, scaling, and maintenance of containerized applications, and we use it in this workshop to host our e-commerce application
Some terminology:
A Kubernetes cluster is a group of machines, called nodes, that work together to run containerized applications.</description></item><item><title>Log on FAQ</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.12/en/s4r/30-initial-tour/99-login-faq/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.12/en/s4r/30-initial-tour/99-login-faq/index.html</guid><description>This FAQ will address some of the more common issues we have encountered when logging into the Workshop.
1. Invite email or password renewal email not arriving The first step to take is to search for an email from noreply@signalfx.com, across all your email folders, as this is the address used to send the invite and password renewal emails. If you don&amp;rsquo;t see the email, check your spam/junk folder.
If you are sure the email does not exist your email, ask the Instructor to verify the email used for the workshop and have him/her resend the invite.</description></item></channel></rss>