<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Custom Service Health Dashboard 🏥 on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.23/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Custom Service Health Dashboard 🏥 on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.23/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dashboard Introduction</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.23/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/1-custom-dashboard/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.23/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/1-custom-dashboard/index.html</guid><description>As we already saved some useful log charts in a dashboard in the Log Observer exercise, we are going to extend that dashboard.
Exercise Go back to your dashboard with the two log charts, by clicking on *Dashboards, and select your dashboard group from the list of linked dashboards at the bottom of the page. This should bring you back to your previously saved dashboard. Even if the log information is useful, it will need more information to have it make sense for our team so let&amp;rsquo;s add a bit more information The first step is adding a description chart to the dashboard.</description></item><item><title>Adding charts to the Service Health Dashboard 📋</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.23/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/2-add-chart/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.23/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/2-add-chart/index.html</guid><description>In this section, we are going to use the Copy and Paste functionality to extend our dashboard. Remember we copied some charts during the APM Service Dashboard section, we will now add those charts to our dashboard.
Exercise Find your Service Health Dashboard. Select the 2+ at the top of the page and select Paste charts, this will create the charts in your custom dashboard. Add sf_environment:[WORKSHOPNAME] and sf_service:payment_service to the override filter box.</description></item><item><title>Create Custom Chart &amp; add to Dashboard</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.23/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/3-custom-chart/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.23/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/3-custom-chart/index.html</guid><description>In this part of the workshop we are going to create a chart that we will add to our dashboard, we will also link it to the detector we previously build. This will allow us to see the behaviour of our test and get alerted if one or more of our test runs breaches its SLA.
Exercise At the top of the dashboard click on the + and select chart. This will bring us to the new chart screen.</description></item></channel></rss>