<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Splunk RUM on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.33/en/s4r/5-rum/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Splunk RUM on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.33/en/s4r/5-rum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1. RUM Dashboard</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.33/en/s4r/5-rum/1-rum-dashboard/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.33/en/s4r/5-rum/1-rum-dashboard/index.html</guid><description>In Splunk Observability Cloud from the main menu, click on RUM. you arrive at the RUM Home page, this view has already been covered in the short introduction earlier.
Exercise Make sure you select your workshop by ensuring the drop-downs are set/selected as follows: The Time frame is set to -15m. The Environment selected is [NAME OF WORKSHOP]-workshop. The App selected is [NAME OF WORKSHOP]-store. The Source is set to All.</description></item><item><title>2. Tag Spotlight</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.33/en/s4r/5-rum/2-tag-spotlight/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.33/en/s4r/5-rum/2-tag-spotlight/index.html</guid><description>Exercise Make sure you are on the Custom Events tab by selecting it.
Have a look at the Custom Event Latency chart. The metrics shown here show the application latency. The comparison metrics to the side show the latency compared to 1 hour ago (which is selected in the top filter bar).
Click on the see all link under the chart title.
In this dashboard view, you are presented with all the tags associated with the RUM data.</description></item><item><title>3. Session Replay</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.33/en/s4r/5-rum/3-session-replay/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.33/en/s4r/5-rum/3-session-replay/index.html</guid><description>Sessions A session is a collection of traces that correspond to the actions a single user takes when interacting with an application. By default, a session lasts until 15 minutes have passed from the last event captured in the session. The maximum session duration is 4 hours.
Exercise In the User Sessions table, click on the top Session ID with the longest Duration (over 20 seconds or longer), this will take you to the RUM Session view.</description></item><item><title>4. User Sessions</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.33/en/s4r/5-rum/4-user-sessions/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.33/en/s4r/5-rum/4-user-sessions/index.html</guid><description>Exercise Close the RUM Session Replay by clicking on the X in the top right corner. We had set a filter on PlaceOrder in the previous exercise. It should be selected here as well, as shown in the screenshot below (1). Note the length of the span, this is the time it took to complete the order, not good! Scroll down the page and you will see the Tags metadata (which is used in Tag Spotlight).</description></item></channel></rss>