<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Splunk Log Observer on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.49/en/s4r/7-log-observer/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Splunk Log Observer on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.49/en/s4r/7-log-observer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1. Log Filtering</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.49/en/s4r/7-log-observer/1-log-filtering/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.49/en/s4r/7-log-observer/1-log-filtering/index.html</guid><description>Log Observer (LO), can be used in multiple ways. In the quick tour, you used the LO no-code interface to search for specific entries in the logs. This section, however, assumes you have arrived in LO from a trace in APM using the Related Content link.
The advantage of this is, as it was with the link between RUM &amp;amp; APM, that you are looking at your logs within the context of your previous actions.</description></item><item><title>2. Viewing Log Entries</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.49/en/s4r/7-log-observer/2-log-entry/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.49/en/s4r/7-log-observer/2-log-entry/index.html</guid><description>Before we look at a specific log line, let&amp;rsquo;s quickly recap what we have done so far and why we are here based on the 3 pillars of Observability:
Metrics Traces Logs Do I have a problem? Where is the problem? What is the problem? Using metrics we identified we have a problem with our application. This was obvious from the error rate in the Service Dashboards as it was higher than it should be.</description></item><item><title>3. Log Timeline Chart</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.49/en/s4r/7-log-observer/3-log-timeline-chart/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.49/en/s4r/7-log-observer/3-log-timeline-chart/index.html</guid><description>Once you have a specific view in Log Observer, it is very useful to be able to use that view in a dashboard, to help in the future with reducing the time to detect or resolve issues. As part of the workshop, we will create an example custom dashboard that will use these charts.
Let&amp;rsquo;s look at creating a Log Timeline chart. The Log Timeline chart is used for visualizing log messages over time.</description></item><item><title>4. Log View Chart</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.49/en/s4r/7-log-observer/4-log-view-chart/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.49/en/s4r/7-log-observer/4-log-view-chart/index.html</guid><description>The next chart type that can be used with logs is the Log View chart type. This chart will allow us to see log messages based on predefined filters.
As with the previous Log Timeline chart, we will add a version of this chart to our Customer Health Service Dashboard:
Exercise After the previous exercise make sure you are still in Log Observer. The filters should be the same as the previous exercise, with the time picker set to the Last 15 minutes and filtering on severity=error, sf_service=paymentservice and sf_environment=[WORKSHOPNAME].</description></item></channel></rss>