<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Standardize Data Collection on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.47/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/2-standardize-data-collection/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Standardize Data Collection on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.47/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/2-standardize-data-collection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Are Tags?</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.47/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/2-standardize-data-collection/1-what-are-tags/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.47/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/2-standardize-data-collection/1-what-are-tags/index.html</guid><description>Tags are key-value pairs that provide additional metadata about metrics, spans in a trace, or logs allowing you to enrich the context of the data you send to Splunk Observability Cloud. There are many tags that are collected by default such as hostname or OS type. Custom tags can be used to provide environment or application specific context. Examples of custom tags include:
Infrastructure specific attributes
What data center a host is in What services are hosted on an instance What team is responsible for a set of hosts Application specific attributes</description></item><item><title>Adding Context With Tags</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.47/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/2-standardize-data-collection/2-adding-context-with-tags/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.47/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/2-standardize-data-collection/2-adding-context-with-tags/index.html</guid><description>When you deployed the OpenTelemetry Demo Application in the Getting Started section of this workshop, you were asked to enter your favorite city. For this workshop, we&amp;rsquo;ll be using that to show the value of custom tags.
For this workshop, the OpenTelemetry collector is pre-configured to use the city you provided as a custom tag called store.location which will be used to emulate Kubernetes Clusters running in different geographic locations. We&amp;rsquo;ll use this tag as a filter to show how you can use Out-of-the-Box integration dashboards to quickly create views for specific teams, applications, or other attributes about your environment.</description></item></channel></rss>