<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Custom Service Health Dashboard 🏥 on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Custom Service Health Dashboard 🏥 on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Enhancing the Dashboard</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/1-custom-dashboard/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/1-custom-dashboard/index.html</guid><description>As we already saved some useful log charts in a dashboard in the Log Observer exercise, we are going to extend that dashboard.
Exercise To get back to your dashboard with the two log charts, click on Dashboards from the main menu and you will be taken to your Team Dashboard view. Under Dashboards click in Search dashboards to search for your Service Health Dashboard group. Click on the name and this will bring up your previously saved dashboard.</description></item><item><title>Adding Copied Charts</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/2-add-chart/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/2-add-chart/index.html</guid><description>In this section, we are going to use the Copy and Paste functionality to extend our dashboard. Remember we copied some charts during the APM Service Dashboard section, we will now add those charts to our dashboard.
Exercise Select the 2+ at the top of the page and select Paste charts, this will create the charts in your custom dashboard. The chart currently shows data for all Environments and Services, so let&amp;rsquo;s add a filter for our environment and the paymentservice.</description></item><item><title>Adding a Custom Chart</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/3-custom-chart/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.39/en/s4r/9-custom-dashboard/3-custom-chart/index.html</guid><description>In this part of the workshop we are going to create a chart that we will add to our dashboard, we will also link it to the detector we previously built. This will allow us to see the behavior of our test and get alerted if one or more of our test runs breach its SLA.
Exercise At the top of the dashboard click on the + and select Chart. First, use the Untitled chart input field and name the chart Overall Test Duration.</description></item></channel></rss>