<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Other Workshops on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.77/other/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Other Workshops on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.77/other/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PetClinic Java Workshop</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.77/other/pet-clinic/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.77/other/pet-clinic/index.html</guid><description>The goal is to walk through the basic steps to configure the following components of the Splunk Observability platform:
Splunk Infrastructure Monitoring (IM) Splunk Zero Configuration Auto Instrumentation for Java (APM) Database Query Performance AlwaysOn Profiling Splunk Real User Monitoring (RUM) Splunk LogsObserver (LO) We will also show the steps about how to clone (download) a sample Java application (Spring PetClinic), as well as how to compile, package and run the application.</description></item><item><title>Monitoring Horizontal Pod Autoscaling in Kubernetes</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.77/other/hpa/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.77/other/hpa/index.html</guid><description>45 minutes This workshop will equip you with the basic understanding of monitoring Kubernetes using the Splunk OpenTelemetry Collector. During the workshop you will deploy PHP/Apache and a load generator.
You will learn about OpenTelemetry Receivers, Kubernetes Namespaces, ReplicaSets, Kubernetes Horizontal Pod AutoScaling and how to monitor all this using the Splunk Observability Cloud. The main learnings from the workshop will be a better understanding of the Kubernetes Navigator (and Dashboards) in Splunk Observability Cloud as well as seeing Kubernetes metrics, events and Detectors.</description></item></channel></rss>