<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>User Profile on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/other/10-oncall/getting_started/index.html</link><description>Recent content in User Profile on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/other/10-oncall/getting_started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Teams</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/other/10-oncall/getting_started/team/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/other/10-oncall/getting_started/team/index.html</guid><description>Aim The aim of this module is for you to complete the first step of Team configuration by adding users to your Team.
1. Find your Team Navigate to the Teams tab on the main toolbar, you should find you that a Team has been created for you as part of the workshop pre-setup and you would have been informed of your Team Name via e-mail.
If you have found your pre-configured Team, skip Step 2.</description></item><item><title>Configure Rotations</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/other/10-oncall/getting_started/rotations/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/other/10-oncall/getting_started/rotations/index.html</guid><description>Aim A rotation is a recurring schedule, that consists of one or more shifts, with members who rotate through a shift.
The aim of this module is for you to configure two example Rotations, and assign Team Members to the Rotations.
Navigate to the Rotations tab on the Teams sub menu, you should have no existing Rotations so we need to create some.
The 1st Rotation you will create is for a follow the sun support pattern where the members of each shift provide cover during their normal working hours within their time zone.</description></item><item><title>Configure Escalation Policies</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/other/10-oncall/getting_started/escalation/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/other/10-oncall/getting_started/escalation/index.html</guid><description>Aim Escalation policies determine who is actually on-call for a given team and are the link to utilizing any rotations that have been created.
The aim of this module is for you to create three different Escalation Policies to demonstrate a number of different features and operating models.
The instructor will start by explaining the concepts before you proceed with the configuration.
Navigate to the Escalation Polices tab on the Teams sub menu, you should have no existing Polices so we need to create some.</description></item><item><title>Creating Routing Keys</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/other/10-oncall/getting_started/routing/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.46/en/other/10-oncall/getting_started/routing/index.html</guid><description>Aim Routing Keys map the incoming alert messages from your monitoring system to an Escalation Policy which in turn sends the notifications to the appropriate team.
Note that routing keys are case insensitive and should only be composed of letters, numbers, hyphens, and underscores.
The aim of this module is for you to create some routing keys and then link them to your Escalation Policies you have created in the previous exercise.</description></item></channel></rss>