<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Splunk APM on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.22/en/s4r/6-apm/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Splunk APM on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.22/en/s4r/6-apm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1. APM Explore</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.22/en/s4r/6-apm/1-apm-explore/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.22/en/s4r/6-apm/1-apm-explore/index.html</guid><description>The APM Service Map displays the dependencies and connections among your instrumented and inferred services in APM. The map is dynamically generated based on your selections in the time range, environment, workflow, service, and tag filters.
When we clicked on the APM link in the RUM waterfall, filters were automatically added to the service map view to show the services that were involved in that WorkFlow Name (frontend:/cart/checkout).
You can see the services involved in the workflow in the Service Map.</description></item><item><title>2. APM Service Dashboard</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.22/en/s4r/6-apm/2-apm-service-dashboard/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.22/en/s4r/6-apm/2-apm-service-dashboard/index.html</guid><description>APM dashboards present request, error, and duration (RED) metrics based on Monitoring MetricSets created from endpoint spans for your services, endpoints, and Business Workflows. They also present related host and Kubernetes metrics to help you determine whether problems are related to the underlying infrastructure.
Note: Need to explain some of the charts in the dashboard, and include using it the exercise
Exercise In the Request rate text chart, click the &amp;hellip; and select Copy.</description></item><item><title>3. APM Tag Spotlight</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.22/en/s4r/6-apm/3-apm-tag-spotlight/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.22/en/s4r/6-apm/3-apm-tag-spotlight/index.html</guid><description>To view the tags for the paymentservice click on the paymentservice and then click on Tag Spotlight in the right-hand side functions pane. Once in Tag Spotlight ensure the toggle Show tags with no values is off.
There are two views available in Tag Spotlight. The default is Request/Errors and the other is Latency.
Request/Error charts display the total number of requests, errors, and root cause errors. The Latency charts display p50, p90, and p99 latency.</description></item><item><title>4. APM Service Breakdown</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.22/en/s4r/6-apm/4-apm-service-breakdown/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.22/en/s4r/6-apm/4-apm-service-breakdown/index.html</guid><description>From the service map view, click on paymentservice to select it. You can use the Breakdown selector to break the service down by any indexed span tag.
More story here &amp;hellip;
Exercise In the right-hand pane there is a button Breakdown . Click on this button to view the tags the service can be broken down by. Select tenant.level. What can you conclude from what you are seeing? Click on gold to select it.</description></item><item><title>5. APM Trace Analyzer</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.22/en/s4r/6-apm/5-apm-trace-analyzer/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.22/en/s4r/6-apm/5-apm-trace-analyzer/index.html</guid><description>In the right-hand pane, click on Traces. To ensure we are using Trace Analyzer make sure the button Switch to Classic View is showing. If it is not, click on Switch to Trace Analyzer .
Splunk Observability Cloud provides several tools for exploring application monitoring data. Trace Analyzer is suited to scenarios where you have high-cardinality, high-granularity searches and explorations to research unknown or new issues.
In Trace Analyzer you can filter traces by any indexed/unindexed span tag.</description></item><item><title>6. APM Waterfall</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.22/en/s4r/6-apm/6-apm-waterfall/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.22/en/s4r/6-apm/6-apm-waterfall/index.html</guid><description>We have arrived at the Trace Waterfall from the Trace Analyzer. A trace is a collection of spans that share the same trace ID, representing a unique transaction handled by your application and its constituent services.
Each span in Splunk APM captures a single operation. Splunk APM considers a span to be an error span if the operation that the span captures results in an error.
Exercise Click on the !</description></item></channel></rss>