<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Logs on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.12/en/tags/logs/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Logs on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.12/en/tags/logs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Splunk4Rookies - Observability</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.12/en/s4r/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.12/en/s4r/index.html</guid><description>In this workshop, we will be showing how Splunk Observability Cloud provides instant visibility of the user experience – from the perspective of the front-end application to its backing services – showing off some of the most compelling product features, and differentiators of the Splunk Observability Cloud Suite:
Infrastructure Monitoring Full-fidelity Real User Monitoring (RUM) Complete end-to-end NoSample™ Full-fidelity trace visibility with Application Performance Monitoring (APM) No code log querying Synthetic Monitoring Finding root cause with tag analytics and error stacks Related content One core tenet in building the Splunk Observability Cloud is unifying telemetry data to create a complete picture of a user’s experience and your application stack.</description></item><item><title>Splunk Log Observer</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.12/en/s4r/70-log-observer/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.12/en/s4r/70-log-observer/index.html</guid><description>Log Observer Connect allows you to seamlessly bring in the same log data from your Splunk Platform into an intuitive and codeless interface designed to help you find and fix problems quickly. You can easily perform log-based analysis and seamlessly correlate your logs with Splunk Infrastructure Monitoring’s real-time metrics and Splunk APM traces in one place.
End-to-end visibility: By combining the powerful logging capabilities of Splunk Platform with Splunk Observability Cloud’s traces and real-time metrics for deeper insights and more context of your hybrid environment.</description></item></channel></rss>