<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Splunk APM on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.33/en/s4r/6-apm/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Splunk APM on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.33/en/s4r/6-apm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1. APM Explore</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.33/en/s4r/6-apm/1-apm-explore/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.33/en/s4r/6-apm/1-apm-explore/index.html</guid><description>The APM Service Map displays the dependencies and connections among your instrumented and inferred services in APM. The map is dynamically generated based on your selections in the time range, environment, workflow, service, and tag filters.
When we clicked on the APM link in the RUM waterfall, filters were automatically added to the service map view to show the services that were involved in that WorkFlow Name (frontend:/cart/checkout).
You can see the services involved in the workflow in the Service Map.</description></item><item><title>2. APM Service Dashboard</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.33/en/s4r/6-apm/2-apm-service-dashboard/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.33/en/s4r/6-apm/2-apm-service-dashboard/index.html</guid><description>Service Dashboard APM Service Dashboards provide request, error, and duration (RED) metrics based on Monitoring MetricSets created from endpoint spans for your services, endpoints, and Business Workflows. If you scroll down the dashboard you will also see the host and Kubernetes-related metrics which help you determine whether there are problems with the underlying infrastructure.
Exercise Check the Time box (1), you can see that the dashboards only show data relevant to the time it took for the APM trace we selected to complete (note that the charts are static).</description></item><item><title>3. APM Tag Spotlight</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.33/en/s4r/6-apm/3-apm-tag-spotlight/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.33/en/s4r/6-apm/3-apm-tag-spotlight/index.html</guid><description>Exercise To view the tags for the paymentservice click on the paymentservice and then click on Tag Spotlight in the right-hand side functions pane (you may need to scroll down depending upon your screen resolution). Once in Tag Spotlight ensure the toggle Show tags with no values is off. There are two views available in Tag Spotlight. The default is Request/Errors and the other is Latency.
Request/Error charts display the total number of requests, errors, and root cause errors.</description></item><item><title>4. APM Service Breakdown</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.33/en/s4r/6-apm/4-apm-service-breakdown/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.33/en/s4r/6-apm/4-apm-service-breakdown/index.html</guid><description>Exercise In the right-hand pane click on the Breakdown . Select tenant.level in the list. This is a tag that exposes the customers&amp;rsquo; status and can be useful to see trends related to customer status. Back in the Service Map Click on gold to select it. Click on Breakdown and select version, this is the tag that exposes the service version. Repeat this for silver and bronze. &amp;#8203; Question Answer What can you conclude from what you are seeing?</description></item><item><title>5. APM Trace Analyzer</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.33/en/s4r/6-apm/5-apm-trace-analyzer/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.33/en/s4r/6-apm/5-apm-trace-analyzer/index.html</guid><description>As Splunk APM provides a NoSample™ end-to-end visibility of every service Splunk APM captures every trace. For this workshop, the Order Confirmation ID is available as a tag. This means that we can use this to search for the exact trace of the poor user experience you encountered earlier in the workshop.
Trace Analyzer Splunk Observability Cloud provides several tools for exploring application monitoring data. Trace Analyzer is suited to scenarios where you have high-cardinality, high-granularity searches and explorations to research unknown or new issues.</description></item><item><title>6. APM Waterfall</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.33/en/s4r/6-apm/6-apm-waterfall/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.33/en/s4r/6-apm/6-apm-waterfall/index.html</guid><description>We have arrived at the Trace Waterfall from the Trace Analyzer. A trace is a collection of spans that share the same trace ID, representing a unique transaction handled by your application and its constituent services.
Each span in Splunk APM captures a single operation. Splunk APM considers a span to be an error span if the operation that the span captures results in an error.
Exercise Click on the !</description></item></channel></rss>