<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>TKO Workshops on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.69/tko/index.html</link><description>Recent content in TKO Workshops on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.69/tko/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Data In (GDI) &amp; OTEL</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.69/tko/session-2/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.69/tko/session-2/index.html</guid><description>45 minutes During this technical workshop you will learn how to:
efficiently deploy complex environments capture metrics from these environments to Splunk Observability Cloud auto-instrument a python application enabling OS logging to Splunk Enterprise via Universal Forwarder In order to simplify the workshop modules, a pre-configured AWS EC2 instance is provided.
By the end of this technical workshop you will have an approach to demonstrating metrics collection for complex environments and services.</description></item><item><title>5. How Platform Engineers Observe Kubernetes</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.69/tko/session-5/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.69/tko/session-5/index.html</guid><description>45 minutes This workshop will equip you with the basic understanding of monitoring Kubernetes using the Splunk OpenTelemetry Collector. During the workshop you will deploy PHP/Apache and a load generator.
You will learn about OpenTelemetry Receivers, Kubernetes Namespaces, ReplicaSets, Kubernetes Horizontal Pod AutoScaling and how to monitor all this using the Splunk Observability Cloud. The main learnings from the workshop will be a better understanding of the Kubernetes Navigator (and Dashboards) in Splunk Observability Cloud as well as seeing Kubernetes metrics, events and Detectors.</description></item><item><title>6. O11y - Distributed Tracing for modern applications</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.69/tko/session-6/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.69/tko/session-6/index.html</guid><description>45 minutes Here at Buttercup Instruments, our business is expanding ! We have recently added 3 new locations, two locations in the USA, Colorado and Chicago and one international location in SRI Lanka !
Our technical staff has already on-boarded the data from these new locations and incorporated them into our inventory application and it is our job to review these improvements and send any issues back to our developers for repairs.</description></item></channel></rss>