<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Other Workshops on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.94/en/other/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Other Workshops on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.94/en/other/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PetClinic Java Workshop</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.94/en/other/pet-clinic/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.94/en/other/pet-clinic/index.html</guid><description>The goal is to walk through the basic steps to configure the following components of the Splunk Observability platform:
Splunk Infrastructure Monitoring (IM) Splunk Zero Configuration Auto Instrumentation for Java (APM) Database Query Performance AlwaysOn Profiling Splunk Real User Monitoring (RUM) RUM to APM Correlation Splunk Log Observer We will also show the steps about how to clone (download) a sample Java application (Spring PetClinic), as well as how to compile, package and run the application.</description></item><item><title>Getting Data In (GDI) with OTel and UF</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.94/en/other/gdi/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.94/en/other/gdi/index.html</guid><description>45 minutes During this technical workshop you will learn how to:
Efficiently deploy complex environments Capture metrics from these environments to Splunk Observability Cloud Auto-instrument a python application Enable OS logging to Splunk Enterprise via Universal Forwarder In order to simplify the workshop modules, a pre-configured AWS EC2 instance is provided.
By the end of this technical workshop you will have an approach to demonstrating metrics collection for complex environments and services.</description></item><item><title>Monitoring Horizontal Pod Autoscaling in Kubernetes</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.94/en/other/hpa/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.94/en/other/hpa/index.html</guid><description>45 minutes This workshop will equip you with the basic understanding of monitoring Kubernetes using the Splunk OpenTelemetry Collector. During the workshop you will deploy PHP/Apache and a load generator.
You will learn about OpenTelemetry Receivers, Kubernetes Namespaces, ReplicaSets, Kubernetes Horizontal Pod AutoScaling and how to monitor all this using the Splunk Observability Cloud. The main learnings from the workshop will be a better understanding of the Kubernetes Navigator (and Dashboards) in Splunk Observability Cloud as well as seeing Kubernetes metrics, events and Detectors.</description></item><item><title>Build a Distributed Trace in Lambda and Kinesis</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.94/en/other/lambda-kinesis/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.94/en/other/lambda-kinesis/index.html</guid><description>45 minutes This workshop will equip you with how a distributed trace is constructed for a small serverless application that runs on AWS Lambda, producing and consuming a message via AWS Kinesis.
We will see how auto-instrumentation works with manual steps to force a Producer function&amp;rsquo;s context to be sent to Consumer function via a Record put on a Kinesis stream.
For this workshop Splunk has prepared an Ubuntu Linux instance in AWS/EC2 all pre-configured for you.</description></item><item><title>Improving MTTR with Custom Tags</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.94/en/other/dev-mttr-custom-tags/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.94/en/other/dev-mttr-custom-tags/index.html</guid><description>45 minutes This workshop will ..
For this workshop Splunk has prepared an Ubuntu Linux instance in AWS/EC2 all pre-configured for you.
To get access to the instance that you will be using in the workshop, please visit the URL provided by the workshop leader.
Splunk Observability Cloud You must have the ability to send traces to Splunk Observability Cloud. If you do not have an account already, please start a trial here: https://www.</description></item></channel></rss>