<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Getting Started on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.47/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/1-getting-started/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Getting Started on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.47/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/1-getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to connect to your workshop environment</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.47/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/1-getting-started/1-access-ec2/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.47/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/1-getting-started/1-access-ec2/index.html</guid><description>How to retrieve the IP address of the AWS/EC2 instance assigned to you. Connect to your instance using SSH, Putty1 or your web browser. Verify your connection to your AWS/EC2 cloud instance. Using Putty (Optional) Using Multipass (Optional) 1. AWS/EC2 IP Address In preparation for the workshop, Splunk has prepared an Ubuntu Linux instance in AWS/EC2.
To get access to the instance that you will be using in the workshop please visit the URL to access the Google Sheet provided by the workshop leader.</description></item><item><title>Deploy OpenTelemetry Demo Applciation</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.47/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/1-getting-started/2-deploy-application/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.47/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/1-getting-started/2-deploy-application/index.html</guid><description>Introduction For this workshop, we&amp;rsquo;ll be using the OpenTelemetry Demo Application running in Kubernetes. This application is for an online retailer and includes more than a dozen services written in many different languages. While metrics, traces, and logs are being collected from this application, this workshop is primarily focused on how Splunk Observability Cloud can be used to more efficiently monitor infrastructure.
Pre-requisites You should have access to the EC2 instance provided in section 1.</description></item></channel></rss>