<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Understand Impact of Changes on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.50/en/scenarios/understand_impact_of_changes/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Understand Impact of Changes on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.50/en/scenarios/understand_impact_of_changes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Build the Sample Application</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.50/en/scenarios/understand_impact_of_changes/1-build-application/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.50/en/scenarios/understand_impact_of_changes/1-build-application/index.html</guid><description>Introduction For this workshop, we&amp;rsquo;ll be using a microservices-based application. This application is for an online retailer and normally includes more than a dozen services. However, to keep the workshop simple, we&amp;rsquo;ll be focusing on two services used by the retailer as part of their payment processing workflow: the credit check service and the credit processor service.
Pre-requisites You will start with an EC2 instance and perform some initial steps in order to get to the following state:</description></item><item><title>What are Tags?</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.50/en/scenarios/understand_impact_of_changes/2-what-are-tags/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.50/en/scenarios/understand_impact_of_changes/2-what-are-tags/index.html</guid><description>To understand why some requests have errors or slow performance, we&amp;rsquo;ll need to add context to our traces. We&amp;rsquo;ll do this by adding tags. But first, let&amp;rsquo;s take a moment to discuss what tags are, and why they&amp;rsquo;re so important for observability.
What are tags? Tags are key-value pairs that provide additional metadata about spans in a trace, allowing you to enrich the context of the spans you send to Splunk APM.</description></item><item><title>Capture Tags with OpenTelemetry</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.50/en/scenarios/understand_impact_of_changes/3-capture-tags/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.50/en/scenarios/understand_impact_of_changes/3-capture-tags/index.html</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s add some tags to our traces, so we can find out why some customers receive a poor experience from our application.
Identify Useful Tags We&amp;rsquo;ll start by reviewing the code for the credit_check function of creditcheckservice (which can be found in the /home/splunk/workshop/tagging/creditcheckservice/main.py file):
@app.route(&amp;#39;/check&amp;#39;) def credit_check(): customerNum = request.args.get(&amp;#39;customernum&amp;#39;) # Get Credit Score creditScoreReq = requests.get(&amp;#34;http://creditprocessorservice:8899/getScore?customernum=&amp;#34; + customerNum) creditScoreReq.raise_for_status() creditScore = int(creditScoreReq.text) creditScoreCategory = getCreditCategoryFromScore(creditScore) # Run Credit Check creditCheckReq = requests.</description></item><item><title>Explore Trace Data</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.50/en/scenarios/understand_impact_of_changes/4-explore-trace-data/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.50/en/scenarios/understand_impact_of_changes/4-explore-trace-data/index.html</guid><description>Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve captured several tags from our application, let&amp;rsquo;s explore some of the trace data we&amp;rsquo;ve captured that include this additional context, and see if we can identify what&amp;rsquo;s causing a poor user experience in some cases.
Use Trace Analyzer Navigate to APM, then select Traces. This takes us to the Trace Analyzer, where we can add filters to search for traces of interest. For example, we can filter on traces where the credit score starts with 7:</description></item><item><title>Index Tags</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.50/en/scenarios/understand_impact_of_changes/5-index-tags/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.50/en/scenarios/understand_impact_of_changes/5-index-tags/index.html</guid><description>Index Tags To use advanced features in Splunk Observability Cloud such as Tag Spotlight, we&amp;rsquo;ll need to first index one or more tags.
To do this, navigate to Settings -&amp;gt; APM MetricSets. Then click the + New MetricSet button.
Let&amp;rsquo;s index the credit.score.category tag by entering the following details (note: since everyone in the workshop is using the same organization, the instructor will do this step on your behalf):
Click Start Analysis to proceed.</description></item><item><title>Use Tags for Troubleshooting</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.50/en/scenarios/understand_impact_of_changes/6-use-tags/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.50/en/scenarios/understand_impact_of_changes/6-use-tags/index.html</guid><description>Using Tag Spotlight Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve indexed the credit.score.category tag, we can use it with Tag Spotlight to troubleshoot our application.
Navigate to APM then click on Tag Spotlight on the right-hand side. Ensure the creditcheckservice service is selected from the Service drop-down (if not already selected).
With Tag Spotlight, we can see 100% of credit score requests that result in a score of impossible have an error, yet requests for all other credit score types have no errors at all!</description></item><item><title>Use Tags with Alerting and Dashboards</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.50/en/scenarios/understand_impact_of_changes/7-alerting-and-dashboards/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.50/en/scenarios/understand_impact_of_changes/7-alerting-and-dashboards/index.html</guid><description>Earlier, we created a Troubleshooting Metric Set on the credit.score.category tag, which allowed us to use Tag Spotlight with that tag and identify a pattern to explain why some users received a poor experience.
In this section of the workshop, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore a related concept: Monitoring MetricSets.
What are Monitoring MetricSets? Monitoring MetricSets go beyond troubleshooting and allow us to use tags for alerting and dashboards.
Create a Monitoring MetricSet Let&amp;rsquo;s navigate to Settings -&amp;gt; APM MetricSets, and click the edit button (i.</description></item><item><title>Summary</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.50/en/scenarios/understand_impact_of_changes/8-summary/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.50/en/scenarios/understand_impact_of_changes/8-summary/index.html</guid><description>In this workshop, we learned the following:
What are tags and why are they such a critical part of making an application observable? How to use OpenTelemetry to capture tags of interest from your application. How to index tags in Splunk Observability Cloud and the differences between Troubleshooting MetricSets and Monitoring MetricSets. How to utilize tags in Splunk Observability Cloud to find “unknown unknowns” using the Tag Spotlight and Dynamic Service Map features.</description></item></channel></rss>