<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops – Incident Lifecycle</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.51/oncall/docs/incident_lifecycle/</link><description>Recent content in Incident Lifecycle on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.51/oncall/docs/incident_lifecycle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Oncall: UI Overview</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.51/oncall/docs/incident_lifecycle/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.51/oncall/docs/incident_lifecycle/overview/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="aim">Aim&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The aim of this module is for you to get more familiar with the Timeline Tab and the filtering features.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-timeline">1. Timeline&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The aim of Splunk On-Call is to make being on call more bearable, and it does this by getting the critical data, to the right people, at the right time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The key to making it work for you is to centralize all your alerting sources, sending them all to the Splunk On-Call platform, then you have a single pane of glass in which to manage all of your alerting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Login to the Splunk On-Call UI and select the &lt;strong>Timeline&lt;/strong> tab on the main menu bar, you should have a screen similar to the following image:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../../images/m7-vo-ui.png" alt="Splunk On-Call UI">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="2-people">2. People&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>On the left we have the &lt;strong>People&lt;/strong> section with the &lt;strong>Teams&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Users&lt;/strong> sub tabs. On the &lt;strong>Teams&lt;/strong> tab, click on &lt;strong>All Teams&lt;/strong> then expand &lt;em>&lt;strong>[Your Teamname]&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Users with the Splunk On-Call Logo against their name are currently on call. Here you can see who is on call within a particular Team, or across all Teams via &lt;strong>Users → On-Call&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you click into one of the currently on call users, you can see their status. It shows which Rotation they are on call for, when their current Shift ends and their next Shift starts (times are displayed in your timezone), what contact methods they have and which Teams they belong to (dummy users such as Hank do not have Contact Methods configured).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../../images/m7-user-detail.png" alt="User Detail">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="3-timeline">3. Timeline&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the centre &lt;strong>Timeline&lt;/strong> section you get a realtime view of what is happening within your environment with the newest messages at the top. Here you can quickly post update messages to make your colleagues aware of important developments etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can filter the view using the buttons on the top toolbar showing only update messages, GitHub integrations, or apply more advanced filters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lets change the Filters settings to streamline your view. Click the &lt;strong>Filters&lt;/strong> button then within the &lt;strong>Routing Keys&lt;/strong> tab change the &lt;strong>Show&lt;/strong> setting from &lt;strong>all routing keys&lt;/strong> to &lt;strong>selected routing keys&lt;/strong>. Change the &lt;strong>My Keys&lt;/strong> value to &lt;strong>all&lt;/strong> and the &lt;strong>Other Keys&lt;/strong> value to &lt;strong>selected&lt;/strong> and deselect all keys under the Other Keys section.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click anywhere outside of the dialogue box to close it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../../images/m7-timeline-filters.png" alt="Timeline Filters">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You will probably now have a much simpler view as you will not currently have Incidents created using your Routing Keys, so you are left with the other types of messages that the Timeline can display.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Click on &lt;strong>Filters&lt;/strong> again, but this time switch to the &lt;strong>Message Types&lt;/strong> tab. Here you control the types of messages that are displayed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, deselect &lt;strong>On-call Changes&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Escalations&lt;/strong>, this will reduce the amount of messages displayed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../../images/m7-timeline-filters-message-types.png" alt="Timeline Filters Message Types">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="4-incidents">4. Incidents&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>On the right we have the &lt;strong>Incidents&lt;/strong> section. Here we get a list of all the incidents within the platform, or we can view a more specific list such as incidents you are specifically assigned to, or for any of the Teams you are a member of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Select the &lt;strong>Team Incidents&lt;/strong> tab you should find that the &lt;strong>Triggered&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Acknowledged&lt;/strong> &amp;amp; &lt;strong>Resolved&lt;/strong> tabs are currently all empty as you have had no incidents logged.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s change that by generating your first incident!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Continue with the &lt;a href="../create_incidents/">Create Incidents&lt;/a>
module.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Oncall: Create Incidents</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.51/oncall/docs/incident_lifecycle/create_incidents/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.51/oncall/docs/incident_lifecycle/create_incidents/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="aim">Aim&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The aim of this module is for you to place yourself &amp;lsquo;On-Call&amp;rsquo; then generate an Incident using the supplied EC2 Instance so you can then work through the lifecycle of an Incident.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="1-on-call">1. On-Call&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before generating any incidents you should assign yourself to the current Shift within your &lt;strong>Follow the Sun Support - Business Hours&lt;/strong> Rotation and also place yourself &lt;strong>On-Call&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>Schedule&lt;/strong> link within your &lt;strong>Team&lt;/strong> in the &lt;strong>People&lt;/strong> section on the left, or navigate to &lt;strong>Teams → [Your Team] → Rotations&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Expand the &lt;strong>Follow the Sun Support - Business Hours&lt;/strong> Rotation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on the &lt;strong>Manage members&lt;/strong> icon (the figures) for the current active shift depending on your timezone
&lt;img src="../../../images/manage-members.png" alt="Manage Members">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use the &lt;strong>Select a user to add&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong> dropdown to add yourself to the shift&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Then click on &lt;strong>Set Current&lt;/strong> next to your name to make yourself the current &lt;strong>on-call&lt;/strong> user within the shift&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You should now get a &lt;strong>Push Notification&lt;/strong> to your phone informing you that &lt;strong>You Are Now On-Call&lt;/strong>
&lt;img src="../../../images/on-duty.png" alt="On Duty">&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="2-trigger-alert">2. Trigger Alert&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Switch back to your shell session connected to your EC2 Instance; all of the following commands will be executed from your Instance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Force the CPU to spike to 100% by running the following command:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-text" data-lang="text">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>openssl speed -multi $(grep -ci processor /proc/cpuinfo)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-text" data-lang="text">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Forked child 0
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>+DT:md4:3:16
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>+R:19357020:md4:3.000000
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>+DT:md4:3:64
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>+R:14706608:md4:3.010000
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>+DT:md4:3:256
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>+R:8262960:md4:3.000000
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>+DT:md4:3:1024
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>This will result in an Alert being generated by Splunk Infrastructure Monitoring which in turn will generate an Incident within Splunk On-Call within a maximum of 10 seconds. This is the default polling time for the OpenTelemetry Collector installed on your instance (note it can be reduced to 1 second).&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Continue with the &lt;a href="../manage_incidents/">Manage Incidents&lt;/a>
module.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Oncall: Manage Incidents</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.51/oncall/docs/incident_lifecycle/manage_incidents/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v4.51/oncall/docs/incident_lifecycle/manage_incidents/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="1-acknowledge">1. Acknowledge&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Use your Splunk On-Call App on your phone to acknowledge the Incident by clicking on the &lt;strong>push notification&lt;/strong> &amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../../images/mobile-notification.png" alt="Push Notification">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;to open the alert in the Splunk On-Call mobile app, then clicking on either the &lt;strong>single tick&lt;/strong> in the top right hand corner, or the &lt;strong>Acknowledge&lt;/strong> link to acknowledge the incident and stop the escalation process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The :fontawesome-solid-check: will then transform into a :fontawesome-solid-check::fontawesome-solid-check:, and the status will change from &lt;strong>TRIGGERED&lt;/strong> to &lt;strong>ACKNOWLEDGED&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Triggered Incident&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Acknowledge Incident&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;img src="../../../images/phone-annotations.png" alt="Acknowledge Alert">&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;img src="../../../images/phone-alert-acknowledged.png" alt="Alert Acknowledged">&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="2-details-and-annotations">2. Details and Annotations&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Still on your phone, select the Alert Details tab. Then on the Web UI, navigate back to &lt;strong>Timeline&lt;/strong>, select &lt;strong>Team Incidents&lt;/strong> on the right, then select &lt;strong>Acknowledged&lt;/strong> and click into the new &lt;strong>Incident&lt;/strong>, this will open up the War Room Dashboard view of the Incident.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You should now have the &lt;strong>Details&lt;/strong> tab displayed on both your Phone and the Web UI. Notice how they both show the exact same information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now select the &lt;strong>Annotations&lt;/strong> tab on both the Phone and the Web UI, you should have a &lt;strong>Graph&lt;/strong> displayed in the UI which is generated by Splunk Infrastructure Monitoring.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../../images/ui-annotations.png" alt="UI Annotations">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On your phone you should get the same image displayed (sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s a simple hyperlink depending on the image size)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../../images/phone-annotations.png" alt="Phone Link">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Splunk On-Call is a &amp;lsquo;Mobile First&amp;rsquo; platform meaning the phone app is full functionality and you can manage an incident directly from your phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the remainder of this module we will focus on the Web UI however please spend some time later exploring the phone app features.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="3-link-to-alerting-system">3. Link to Alerting System&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Sticking with the Web UI, click the &lt;strong>2. Alert Details in SignalFx&lt;/strong> link.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../../images/alert-details-in-sfx.png" alt="Alert Details">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This will open a new browser tab and take you directly to the Alert within Splunk Infrastructure Monitoring where you could then progress your troubleshooting using the powerful tools built into its UI.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../../images/sfx-alert-details.png" alt="SFX Alert Details">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, we are focussing on Splunk On-Call so close this tab and return to the Splunk On-Call UI.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="4-similar-incidents">4. Similar Incidents&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>What if Splunk On-Call could identify previous incidents within the system which may give you a clue to the best way to tackle this incident.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Similar Incidents&lt;/strong> tab does exactly that, surfacing previous incidents allowing you to look at them and see what actions were taken to resolve them, actions which could be easily repeated for this incident.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../../images/similar-incidents.png" alt="Similar Incidents">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="5-timeline">5 Timeline&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>On right we have a Time Line view where you can add messages and see the history of previous alerts and interactions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../../images/war-room-dashboard.png" alt="Incident View">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="6-add-responders">6 Add Responders&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>On the far left you have the option of allocating additional resources to this incident by clicking on the &lt;strong>Add Responders&lt;/strong> link.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../../images/add-responders.png" alt="add-responders">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This allows you build a virtual team specific to this incident by adding other Teams or individual Users, and also share details of a &lt;strong>Conference Bridge&lt;/strong> where you can all get together and collaborate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../../images/conference-bridge.png" alt="Conference Bridge">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once the system has built up some incident data history, it will use Machine Learning to suggest Teams and Users who have historically worked on similar incidents, as they may be best placed to help resolve this incident quickly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can select different Teams and/or Users and also choose from a pre-configured conference bridge, or populate the details of a new bridge from your preferred provider.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We do not need to add any Responders in this exercise so close the &lt;strong>Add Responders&lt;/strong> dialogue by clicking &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="7-reroute">7 Reroute&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If it&amp;rsquo;s decided that maybe the incident could be better dealt with by a different Team, the call can be &lt;strong>Rerouted&lt;/strong> by clicking the &lt;strong>Reroute&lt;/strong> Button at the top of the left hand panel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../../images/reroute1.png" alt="Reroute">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a similar method to that used in the Add Responders dialogue, you can select Teams or Users to Reroute the Incident to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../../images/reroute2.png" alt="Reroute Incident">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We do not need to actually Reroute in this exercise so close the &lt;strong>Reroute Incident&lt;/strong> dialogue by clicking &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="8-snooze">8 Snooze&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can also &lt;strong>snooze&lt;/strong> this incident by clicking on the &lt;strong>alarm clock&lt;/strong> Button at the top of the left hand panel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../../images/snooze1.png" alt="Snnoze">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can enter an amount of time upto 24 hours to snooze the incident. This action will be tracked in the Timeline, and when the time expires the paging will restart.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is useful for low priority incidents, enabling you to put them on a back burner for a few hours, but it ensures they do not get forgotten thanks to the paging process starting again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../../images/snooze2.png" alt="Snooze Incident">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We do not need to actually Snooze in this exercise so close the &lt;strong>Snooze Incident&lt;/strong> dialogue by clicking &lt;strong>Cancel&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="9-action-tracking">9 Action Tracking&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Now lets fix this issue and update the Incident with what we did. Add a new message at the top of the right hand panel such as &lt;strong>Discovered rogue process, terminated it&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../../images/time-line-update-message.png" alt="Add Message">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All the actions related to the Incident will be recorded here, and can then be summarized is a &lt;strong>Post Incident Review Report&lt;/strong> available from the &lt;strong>Reports&lt;/strong> tab&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="10-resolution">10 Resolution&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Now kill off the process we started in the VM to max out the CPU by switching back the Shell session for the VM and pressing &lt;strong>ctrl+c&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Within no more than 10 seconds SignalFx should detect the new CPU value, clear the alert state in SignalFx, then automatically update the Incident in VictorOps marking it as &lt;strong>Resolved&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../../images/m7-resolved.png" alt="Resolved">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As we have two way integration between Splunk Infrastructure Monitoring and Splunk On-Call we could have also marked the incident as Resolved in Splunk On-Call, and this would have resulted in the alert in Splunk Infrastructure Monitoring being resolved as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>That completes this introduction to Splunk On-Call, but feel free to checkout the more advanced modules which will be published in the coming weeks in the &lt;strong>Optional Modules&lt;/strong> section. These will cover topics such as:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Reporting&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Using the API&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Webhooks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Alert Rules Engine&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Maintenance Mode&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>