<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Splunk4Rookies - Observability on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.15/en/s4r/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Splunk4Rookies - Observability on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.15/en/s4r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Workshop Overview</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.15/en/s4r/1-workshop-goals/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.15/en/s4r/1-workshop-goals/index.html</guid><description>1. Introduction The goal of this workshop is to experience an issue and use Splunk Observability Cloud to troubleshoot and identify the root cause. For this, we have provided a complete microservices-based application running in Kubernetes that has been instrumented to send metrics, traces, and logs to Splunk Observability Cloud.
2. OpenTelemetry A Quick introduction to why OpenTelemetry and why is it important for Observability.
3. A tour of the Splunk Observability User Interface A walkthrough of the various components of Splunk Observability Cloud showing you how to easily navigate the 5 main components:- APM, RUM, Log Observer, Synthetics and Infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>What is OpenTelemetry &amp; why should you care?</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.15/en/s4r/2-opentelemetry/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.15/en/s4r/2-opentelemetry/index.html</guid><description>With the rise of cloud computing, microservices architectures, and ever-more complex business requirements, the need for Observability has never been greater. Observability is the ability to understand the internal state of a system by examining its outputs. In the context of software, this means being able to understand the internal state of a system by examining its telemetry data, which includes metrics, traces, and logs.
To make a system observable, it must be instrumented.</description></item><item><title>UI - Quick Tour</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.15/en/s4r/3-initial-tour/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.15/en/s4r/3-initial-tour/index.html</guid><description>A walkthrough of the various components of Splunk Observability Cloud showing you how to easily navigate the 5 main components:- APM, RUM, Log Observer, Synthetics and Infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>TO BE REMOVED</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.15/en/s4r/4-to-be-removed/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.15/en/s4r/4-to-be-removed/index.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>5. Shopping at the Online Boutique</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.15/en/s4r/5-online-boutique/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.15/en/s4r/5-online-boutique/index.html</guid><description>The purpose of this exercise is for you to interact with the Online Boutique web application. This is a sample application that is used to demonstrate the capabilities of Splunk Observability Cloud. The application is a simple e-commerce site that allows you to browse items, add them to your cart, and then checkout.
The application will already be deployed for you and your instructor will provide you with a link to the Online Boutique website.</description></item><item><title>Real User Monitoring Exercise</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.15/en/s4r/6-rum/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.15/en/s4r/6-rum/index.html</guid><description>We are going to examine the real user data that has been provided by the telemetry received from all participants&amp;rsquo; browser sessions. The goal is to find a browser, mobile or tablet session that performed poorly and begin the troubleshooting process.</description></item><item><title>Splunk APM</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.15/en/s4r/7-apm/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.15/en/s4r/7-apm/index.html</guid><description>Discover the power of full end-to-end visibility by jumping from a RUM trace (frontend) to an APM trace (backend). All the services are sending telemetry (traces and spans) that Splunk Observability Cloud can visualize, analyze and use to detect anomalies and errors.
RUM and APM are two sides of the same coin. RUM is the client-side view of the application and APM is the server-side view. In this section, we will use APM to drilldown and identify where the problem is.</description></item><item><title>Splunk Log Observer</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.15/en/s4r/8-log-observer/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.15/en/s4r/8-log-observer/index.html</guid><description>Using content related to the APM trace we just looked at, we will now use Splunk Log Observer to drill down further into the issue to understand exactly what the problem is.
Related Content is a powerful feature that allows you to jump from one component to another and is available for metrics, traces and logs.</description></item><item><title>Splunk Synthetics</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.15/en/s4r/9-synthetics/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.15/en/s4r/9-synthetics/index.html</guid><description>Wouldn’t it be great if we could have 24/7 monitoring of our application, and be alerted when there is a problem? This is where Synthetics comes in. We will show you a simple test that runs every 1 minute and checks the performance and availability of a typical user journey through the Online Boutique.</description></item><item><title>War Room Dashboard</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.15/en/s4r/10-war-room/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.15/en/s4r/10-war-room/index.html</guid><description>WIP WIP WIP WIP WIP Flow:
Go back to your war room dashboard with the two log charts It can use a bit more information, so let&amp;rsquo;s add request rate charts and Error rate charts. Revisit APM, Select explore, and select the payment service. Select the Dashboard option on the top right of the screen. You should now be on the APM services map with the workshop and payment service selected.</description></item><item><title>Workshop Wrap-up</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.15/en/s4r/11-wrap-up/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.15/en/s4r/11-wrap-up/index.html</guid><description>This wraps up the Splunk for Rookies Workshop of the Splunk Observability Cloud. We were able to:
Understand what real users were experiencing See how we can detect these issues through Detectors, Dashboards and Synthetic Tests Troubleshoot a particularly long page load, by following its trace across the front and back end and right to the log entries. Use Tag Spotlight, in both RUM and APM, to understand blast radius and context for our performance issues and errors.</description></item></channel></rss>