<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Workshop Setup on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.37/en/workshop-setup/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Workshop Setup on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.37/en/workshop-setup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1. Using SWiPE</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.37/en/workshop-setup/1-swipe/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.37/en/workshop-setup/1-swipe/index.html</guid><description>Configure Your Org Using SWiPE SWiPE is an online tool to help configure a workshop environment in Splunk Observability Cloud and is available here.
Info SWiPE does not provision EC2 instances - these are provisioned using Splunk Show.
SWiPE will configure the following:
Create and invite users to the Org. Create a .csv file containing the e-mail addresses (one per line) or copy and paste e-mail addresses (one per line). Create a team and add users to the team.</description></item><item><title>2. Using Splunk Show</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.37/en/workshop-setup/2-splunk-show/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.37/en/workshop-setup/2-splunk-show/index.html</guid><description>Provision the EC2 Instances Using Splunk Show Please visit Splunk Show to provision your workshop instance(s).
Select the desired Content Type as follows:
Pre-configured Instances - select this if you need the OpenTelemetry Collector and the application pre-deployed for a less technical audience. Attendees will only require a browser to complete the workshop. This option must be selected if you want to run the Splunk4Rookies - Observability Workshop.
Select Normal Workshop only!</description></item><item><title>3. Workshop Clean-up</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.37/en/workshop-setup/3-clean-up/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.37/en/workshop-setup/3-clean-up/index.html</guid><description>Workshop Clean-up Once you have completed your workshop session please remember to go back and clean up the environment using SWiPE. Also, ensure your workshop instances are deleted to save costs.
SWiPE will complete the following:
Delete all the users associated with the workshop Delete the team Delete the tokens (INGEST, API and RUM) Delete user dashboards SWiPE also provides some advanced features for deleting tokens and detectors etc., and these must be used with caution.</description></item><item><title>4. Trial Org Configuration</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.37/en/workshop-setup/4-org-configuration/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.37/en/workshop-setup/4-org-configuration/index.html</guid><description>Log Observer Connect The workshops require a Log Observer Connect configuration to be completed. This is required to be able to send logs from the workshop instances to Splunk Cloud/Enterprise.
Log Field Aliasing Log Field Aliasing configuration is required to ensure Related Content works correctly in the Splunk Observability Cloud UI. Configure as per the following:
APM MetricSets APM MetricSets need to be configured for the tags in the screenshot below.</description></item></channel></rss>