<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Optimize Cloud Monitoring on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Optimize Cloud Monitoring on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Started</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/1-getting-started/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/1-getting-started/index.html</guid><description>During this technical Optimize Cloud Monitoring Workshop, you will build out an environment based on a lightweight Kubernetes1 cluster.
To simplify the workshop modules, a pre-configured AWS/EC2 instance is provided.
The instance is pre-configured with all the software required to deploy the Splunk OpenTelemetry Connector2 and the microservices-based OpenTelemetry Demo Application3 in Kubernetes which has been instrumented using OpenTelemetry to send metrics, traces, spans and logs.
This workshop will introduce you to the benefits of standardized data collection, how content can be re-used across teams, correlating metrics and logs, and creating detectors to fire alerts.</description></item><item><title>Standardize Data Collection</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/2-standardize-data-collection/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/2-standardize-data-collection/index.html</guid><description>Why Standards Matter As cloud adoption grows, we often face requests to support new technologies within a diverse landscape, posing challenges in delivering timely content. Take, for instance, a team containerizing five workloads on AWS requiring EKS visibility. Usually, this involves assisting with integration setup, configuring metadata, and creating dashboards and alerts—a process that&amp;rsquo;s both time-consuming and increases administrative overhead and technical debt.
Splunk Observability Cloud was designed to handle customers with a diverse set of technical requirements and stacks – from monolithic to microservices architectures, from homegrown applications to Software-as-a-Service.</description></item><item><title>Reuse Content Across Teams</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/3-reuse-content-across-teams/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/3-reuse-content-across-teams/index.html</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s rapidly evolving technological landscape, where hybrid and cloud environments are becoming the norm, the need for effective monitoring and troubleshooting solutions has never been more critical. However, managing the elasticity and complexity of these modern infrastructures poses a significant challenge for teams across various industries. One of the primary pain points encountered in this endeavor is the inadequacy of existing monitoring and troubleshooting experiences.
Traditional monitoring approaches often fall short in addressing the intricacies of hybrid and cloud environments.</description></item><item><title>Correlate Metrics and Logs</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/4-correlate-metrics-logs/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/4-correlate-metrics-logs/index.html</guid><description>Correlating infrastructure metrics and logs is often a challenging task, primarily due to inconsistencies in naming conventions across various data sources, including hosts operating on different systems. However, leveraging the capabilities of OpenTelemetry can significantly simplify this process. With OpenTelemetry&amp;rsquo;s robust framework, which offers rich metadata and attribution, metrics, traces, and logs can seamlessly correlate using standardized field names. This automated correlation not only alleviates the burden of manual effort but also enhances the overall observability of the system.</description></item><item><title>Improve Timeliness of Alerts</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/5-improve-alert-timeliness/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/5-improve-alert-timeliness/index.html</guid><description>When monitoring hybrid and cloud environments, ensuring timely alerts for critical infrastructure and applications poses a significant challenge. Typically, this involves crafting intricate queries, meticulously scheduling searches, and managing alerts across various monitoring solutions. Moreover, the proliferation of disparate alerts generated from identical data sources often results in unnecessary duplication, contributing to alert fatigue and noise within the monitoring ecosystem.
In this section, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how Splunk Observability Cloud addresses these challenges by enabling the effortless creation of alert criteria.</description></item><item><title>Conclusion</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/6-workshop-conclusion/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.51/en/scenarios/optimize_monitoring/6-workshop-conclusion/index.html</guid><description>Today you’ve seen how Splunk Observability Cloud can help you overcome many of the challenges you face monitoring hybrid and cloud environments. You’ve demonstrated how Splunk Observability Cloud streamlines operations with standardized data collection and tags, ensuring consistency across all IT infrastructure. The Unified Service Telemetry has been a game-changer, providing in-context metrics, logs, and trace data that make troubleshooting swift and efficient. By enabling the reuse of content across teams, you’re minimizing technical debt and bolstering the performance of our monitoring systems.</description></item></channel></rss>