<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Splunk Observability Workshops on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Splunk Observability Workshops on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Splunk4Rookies - Observability Cloud</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/s4r/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/s4r/index.html</guid><description>In this workshop, we will be showing how Splunk Observability Cloud provides instant visibility of the user experience – from the perspective of the front-end application to its back-end services – Letting you experience some of the most compelling product features and differentiators of Splunk Observability Cloud:
Infrastructure Monitoring Full-fidelity Real User Monitoring (RUM) Complete end-to-end NoSample™ Full-fidelity trace visibility with Application Performance Monitoring (APM) No code log querying Synthetic Monitoring Finding root causes with tag analytics and error stacks Related content A key factor in building the Splunk Observability Cloud is to unify telemetry data to create a complete picture of an end-user experience and your application stack.</description></item><item><title>Scenarios</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/scenarios/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/scenarios/index.html</guid><description>Optimize Cloud MonitoringThis scenario is for ITOps teams managing a hybrid infrastructure that need to troubleshoot cloud-native performance issues, by correlating real-time metrics with logs to troubleshoot faster, improve MTTD/MTTR, and optimize costs.
Understand Impact of ChangesThis scenario helps SREs identify the impact of planned and unplanned changes to their environment so that they can address issues quickly to ensure the performance of key customer transactions.
Debug Problems in MicroservicesThis scenario helps software developers to make debugging problems in microservices easier, faster, and more cost-effective for platform engineering teams rolling out standardized tooling.</description></item><item><title>Ninja Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/other/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/other/index.html</guid><description>Splunk IMSplunk delivers real-time monitoring and troubleshooting to help you maximize infrastructure performance with complete visibility.
Splunk APMSplunk APM is a NoSample™ Full-fidelity application performance monitoring and troubleshooting solution for cloud-native, microservices-based applications.
Auto-Instrumentation WorkshopsAuto-Instrumentation Workshops
Monitoring Horizontal Pod Autoscaling in KubernetesThis workshop will equip you with the basic understanding of monitoring Kubernetes using the Splunk OpenTelemetry Collector
Making Your Observability Cloud Native With OpenTelemetryLearn the concepts of the OpenTelemetry Collector and how to use it to send data to Splunk Observability Cloud.</description></item><item><title>Conf24 Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/conf24/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/conf24/index.html</guid><description>Workshop using the Java microservices Pet Clinic demo (Kubernetes-based).Learn how to enable Open Telemetry (Auto) Instrumentation for your Java-based application running in Kubernetes. Experience real-time monitoring and troubleshooting to help you maximize application behavior with end-to-end visibility.</description></item><item><title>Resources</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/resources/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/resources/index.html</guid><description>Frequently Asked QuestionsA collection of the common questions and their answers associated with Observability, DevOps, Incident Response and Splunk On-Call.
Dimension, Properties and TagsOne conversation that frequently comes up is Dimensions vs Properties and when you should use one verus the other.
Naming Conventions for Tagging with OpenTelemetry and SplunkWhen deploying OpenTelemetry in a large organization, it’s critical to define a standardized naming convention for tagging, and a governance process to ensure the convention is adhered to.</description></item><item><title>Workshop Setup</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/workshop-setup/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.48/en/workshop-setup/index.html</guid><description>Welcome to the Observability Workshop Setup Guide. This guide will walk you through the steps required to set up your workshop environments.
Existing Workshop Orgs The following Organizations can be used for running Observability Workshops. They have all the features enabled to successfully run any of the available workshops:
CoE Workshop EMEA (EU0) Observability Workshop EMEA (EU0) Observability Workshop AMER (US1) APAC-O11y-Workshop (US1) Trial Orgs It is also possible to create workshop environments in any trial Org.</description></item></channel></rss>