<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Infrastructure Overview :: Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.71/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/6-infrastructure-home/index.html</link><description>Splunk Infrastructure Monitoring (IM) is a market-leading monitoring and observability service for hybrid cloud environments. Built on a patented streaming architecture, it provides a real-time solution for engineering teams to visualize and analyze performance across infrastructure, services, and applications in a fraction of the time and with greater accuracy than traditional solutions.
OpenTelemetry standardization: Gives you full control over your data — freeing you from vendor lock-in and implementing proprietary agents.
Splunk’s OTel Collector: Seamless installation and dynamic configuration, auto-discovers your entire stack in seconds for visibility across clouds, services, and systems.
300+ Easy-to-use OOTB content: Pre-built navigators and dashboards, deliver immediate visualizations of your entire environment so that you can interact with all your data in real time.
Kubernetes navigator: Provides an instant, comprehensive out-of-the-box hierarchical view of nodes, pods, and containers. Ramp up even the most novice Kubernetes user with easy-to-understand interactive cluster maps.
AutoDetect alerts and detectors: Automatically identify the most important metrics, out-of-the-box, to create alert conditions for detectors that accurately alert from the moment telemetry data is ingested and use real-time alerting capabilities for important notifications in seconds.
Log views in dashboards: Combine log messages and real-time metrics on one page with common filters and time controls for faster in-context troubleshooting.
Metrics pipeline management: Control metrics volume at the point of ingest without re-instrumentation with a set of aggregation and data-dropping rules to store and analyze only the needed data. Reduce metrics volume and optimize observability spend.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.71/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/6-infrastructure-home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Infrastructure Navigators</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.71/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/6-infrastructure-home/1-infrastructure-home/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.71/en/s4r/3-quick-tour/6-infrastructure-home/1-infrastructure-home/index.html</guid><description>Click on Infrastructure in the main menu, the Infrastructure Home Page is made up of 4 distinct sections.
Onboarding Pane: Training videos and links to documentation to get you started with Splunk Infrastructure Monitoring. Time &amp; Filter Pane: Time window (not configurable at the top level) Integrations Pane: List of all the technologies that are sending metrics to Splunk Observability Cloud. Tile Pane: Total number of services being monitored broken down by integration. Using the Infrastructure pane, we can select the infrastructure/technology we are interested in, let’s do that now.</description></item></channel></rss>