<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Setting up automatic discovery and configuration for APM :: Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.70/en/ninja-workshops/1-automatic-discovery/2-petclinic-kubernetes/4-apm/index.html</link><description>In this section we will enable automatic discovery and configuration for the Java services running in Kubernetes. This means that the OpenTelemetry Collector will look for Pod annotations that indicate that the Java application should be instrumented with the Splunk OpenTelemetry Java agent. This will allow us to get traces, spans, and profiling data from the Java services running on the cluster.
automatic discovery and configuration It is important to understand that automatic discovery and configuration is designed to get trace, span &amp; profiling data out of your application, without requiring code changes or recompilation.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.70/en/ninja-workshops/1-automatic-discovery/2-petclinic-kubernetes/4-apm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Patching the Deployment</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.70/en/ninja-workshops/1-automatic-discovery/2-petclinic-kubernetes/4-apm/1-patching-deployment/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.70/en/ninja-workshops/1-automatic-discovery/2-petclinic-kubernetes/4-apm/1-patching-deployment/index.html</guid><description>To configure automatic discovery and configuration the deployments need to be patched to add the instrumentation annotation. Once patched, the OpenTelemetry Collector will inject the automatic discovery and configuration library and the Pods will be restarted in order to start sending traces and profiling data. First, confirm that the api-gateway does not have the splunk-otel-java image.
​ Describe api-gateway Describe Output kubectl describe pods api-gateway | grep Image: Image: quay.io/phagen/spring-petclinic-api-gateway:0.0.2 Next, enable the Java automatic discovery and configuration for all of the services by adding the annotation to the deployments. The following command will patch the all deployments. This will trigger the OpenTelemetry Operator to inject the splunk-otel-java image into the Pods:</description></item><item><title>Viewing the data in Splunk APM</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.70/en/ninja-workshops/1-automatic-discovery/2-petclinic-kubernetes/4-apm/2-apm-data/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.70/en/ninja-workshops/1-automatic-discovery/2-petclinic-kubernetes/4-apm/2-apm-data/index.html</guid><description>Log in to Splunk Observability Cloud, from the left-hand menu click on APM to see the data generated by the traces from the newly instrumented services. Change the Environment filter (1) to the name of your workshop instance in the dropdown box (this will be &lt;INSTANCE>-workshop where INSTANCE is the value from the shell script you ran earlier) and make sure it is the only one selected.</description></item></channel></rss>