<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Resources on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.34/en/resources/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Resources on Splunk Observability Cloud Workshops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.34/en/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Frequently Asked Questions</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.34/en/resources/faq/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.34/en/resources/faq/index.html</guid><description>A collection of the common questions and their answers associated with Observability, DevOps, Incident Response and Splunk On-Call.
Q: Alerts v. Incident Response v. Incident Management A: Alerts, Incident Response and Incident Management are related functions. Together they comprise the incident response and resolution process.
Monitoring and Observability tools send alerts to incident response platforms. Those platforms take a collection of alerts and correlate them into incidents.
Those incidents are recorded into incident management (ITSM) platforms for record.</description></item><item><title>Dimension, Properties and Tags</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.34/en/resources/dimensions_properties_tags/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.34/en/resources/dimensions_properties_tags/index.html</guid><description>Applying context to your metrics One conversation that frequently comes up is Dimensions vs Properties and when you should use one verus the other. Instead of starting off with their descriptions it makes sense to understand how we use them and how they are similar, before diving into their differences and examples of why you would use one or the other.
How are Dimensions and Properties similar? The simplest answer is that they are both metadata key:value pairs that add context to our metrics.</description></item><item><title>Naming Conventions for Tagging with OpenTelemetry and Splunk</title><link>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.34/en/resources/otel_tagging/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://splunk.github.io/observability-workshop/v5.34/en/resources/otel_tagging/index.html</guid><description>Introduction When deploying OpenTelemetry in a large organization, it’s critical to define a standardized naming convention for tagging, and a governance process to ensure the convention is adhered to.
This ensures that MELT data collected via OpenTelemetry can be efficiently utilized for alerting, dashboarding, and troubleshooting purposes. It also ensures that users of Splunk Observability Cloud can quickly find the data they’re looking for.
Naming conventions also ensure that data can be aggregated effectively.</description></item></channel></rss>